<object clone="/usr/SkotOS/obj/help" owner="SkotOS">
  <Help:Node title="General Concepts: Character">
    <Log:Description>
       Title: Character<br/><br/> When entering a Skotos Tech game or Theatre, you have the option to become a wholely unique character that is dwelling in a different time and place. As you interact with other people as your alternate person you'll move forward your In Character (IC) experience.<br/> Although you may be involved in situations that are intense, humorous, or even romantic, it's always important to remember that you're still playing a character within a game. Your character is separate from your player, or at least should be. This is pretend, and in pretending you can often do things that you, the player, would not.<br/> {? equal | $(theatre.gameid) | Marrach | Castle Marrach is fairly strict about staying In Character while you're within the game. The game has been created, coded, and tested to establish a mood and texture conducive to an IC experience. Excessive Out Of Character (OOC) talking during a scene is often viewed as disruptive and rude.<br/> There is a fine line between excessive and acceptable, which is best left to the judgment of those involved in a scene, but it is safe to say that anything above and beyond a simple greeting or polite clarification to an IC action is considered excessive. There are OOC speaking functions, but they are not to be abused in the interest of retaining as much IC continuity as possible.|Different games will have different tolerances for how much In Character (IC) and Out Of Character (OOC) discussion is allowed. In general, Theatres are fairly open, but full games may be much more restrictive about OOC discussions.} <br/><br/> See Also: Communicate, Fun, Roleplaying, Theme<br/>
    </Log:Description>
    <Help:Keywords>
      <Help:Keyword keyword="character"/>
    </Help:Keywords>
    <Core:Properties>
      <Core:Property property="revisions">
         (\{ 1135365933, "-", "SYNC" \})
      </Core:Property>
    </Core:Properties>
    <Ur:UrObject/>
  </Help:Node>
</object>
