<object clone="/usr/SkotOS/obj/help" owner="SkotOS">
  <Help:Node title="General Concepts: Clothing">
    <Log:Description>
       <br/>Title: Clothing<br/> Important Commands: remove, wear, wield<br/> Syntax: "wear tunic", "wear crown", "remove cap"<br/><br/> {? equal | $(theatre.gameid) | Marrach | When you arrive in Castle Marrach you will find yourself swathed in linens.|When you begin playing in a Skotos Theatre or game you will find yourself dressed in standard clothes for the period.} However, much more grand attire is possible.<br/> {? equal | $(theatre.gameid) | Marrach | To get better clothing you will want to seek out the tailors or seamstress on the fourth floor. Use the north stairwell of the castle to go up to the fourth floor.  The seamstresses and tailors can be found to the far west. Seamstress and tailor characters can also usually be found who will dye and tailor garments.  Later, when you grow in favour you may gain access to the better clothiers in the Inner Bailey. | In many of Skotos' games and Theatres tailors and seamstresses will be available to help you improve your clothing. Wander around and ask other characters if these CNPCs are present.}<br/> Clothing is worn in layers, just as it is in the real world. A gown goes over under garments. A cloak goes over a gown. You wear and remove clothing according to this logic. Clothing covers specific parts of the body, and, therefore, it is impossible to see any body part or clothing that is covered with another garment.<br/> Weapons can also be found in many games. They are equipped with the $(udat.chatchar)WIELD command.<br/><br/> See Also: Containers, Manipulation, Seamstress, Tailor<br/>
    </Log:Description>
    <Help:Keywords>
      <Help:Keyword keyword="clothes"/>
      <Help:Keyword keyword="clothing"/>
    </Help:Keywords>
    <Core:Properties>
      <Core:Property property="revisions">
         (\{ 1135365935, "-", "SYNC" \})
      </Core:Property>
    </Core:Properties>
    <Ur:UrObject/>
  </Help:Node>
</object>
