<object clone="/usr/SkotOS/obj/help" owner="SkotOS">
  <Help:Node title="General Concepts: Clustering">
    <Log:Description>
       <br/>Title: Clustering<br/> Important Commands: look, examine<br/><br/> In real life when you look at an area, you don't tend to differentiate every item. Instead, you tend to see categories of things, and only make out specifics when you look closer. <br/> For example, when I look at my desk, I see: a calculator, a computer, a plastic spider, five folders, and a lot of paper. It's only when I actually look at those folders that I see that one relates to health insurance, another to game proposals, and another three to paid bills. And it's only when I look at those folders of paid bills that I see one is for local telephone, one is for long distance telephone, and one is for Internet services.<br/> Skotos Theatres and games reflect this paradigm. If a room is full of lots of different things, those things get clustered into categories. By looking at those categories, you can make out specifics. In a room, you might see a cluster of six people or a cluster of five pieces of furniture. By typing $(udat.chatchar)LOOK AT [CATEGORY] (i.e., "$(udat.chatchar)look at people"), you'll get more specifics. <br/> If a category was very crowded, you may see subcategories before you finally got down to specific objects ("a hundred and three people" might break down into "fifty-four men and forty-nine women" and those "forty-nine women" might break into "eight ladies" and "forty-one guests"). Just continue using the "look" command.<br/><br/> See Also: Perception<br/>
    </Log:Description>
    <Help:Keywords>
      <Help:Keyword keyword="cluster"/>
      <Help:Keyword keyword="clustering"/>
      <Help:Keyword keyword="gather"/>
      <Help:Keyword keyword="gathering"/>
      <Help:Keyword keyword="group"/>
    </Help:Keywords>
    <Core:Properties>
      <Core:Property property="revisions">
         (\{ 1135365936, "-", "SYNC" \})
      </Core:Property>
    </Core:Properties>
    <Ur:UrObject/>
  </Help:Node>
</object>
