<object clone="/usr/SkotOS/obj/help" owner="SkotOS">
  <Help:Node title="General Concepts: Combat">
    <Log:Description>
       Title: Combat<br/> {? equal | $(theatre.gameid) | Marrach | Important Commands: advance, cut, duel, dodge, feint, guard, rest, retire, surrender, thrust, health<br/><br/> The only type of combat allowed in Castle Marrach is dueling. Dueling is meant to be a formal affair requiring the approval of the Queen, the Consort, or the Chamberlain. A delay of a day and the selection of seconds are also required. However, sometimes these rules are broken.<br/> Duels are begun with the $(udat.chatchar)DUEL command. Both sides must consent before a duel is actually begun.<br/> Each combatant enters a series of maneuvers while in a duel. These commands include attacks ($(udat.chatchar)CUT, $(udat.chatchar)FEINT, $(udat.chatchar)THRUST), defenses ($(udat.chatchar)DODGE, $(udat.chatchar)GUARD), and movement ($(udat.chatchar)ADVANCE, $(udat.chatchar)RETIRE). $(udat.chatchar)REST allows you to regain your wits, but is dangerous if your opponent is still attacking. $(udat.chatchar)SURRENDER ends a duel.<br/> There is a clear winner and loser when a duel has ended. It is a point of honor among duelists to accept that the winner was correct and the loser wrong concerning the matter that initiated the duel.<br/> | {? equal | $(theatre.gameid) | GES |<br/>In Galactic Emperor: Succession, combat is carried out through the treachery of the Imperial vote and amongst the stars, against the Vl'hurgh.| <br/>Certain Skotos games include combat systems, as appropriate for the mood and milleu of the the individual world.}}<br/> <br/> See Also: Consent, Death, Injury<br/>
    </Log:Description>
    <Help:Keywords>
      <Help:Keyword keyword="combat"/>
      <Help:Keyword keyword="duel"/>
      <Help:Keyword keyword="dueling"/>
      <Help:Keyword keyword="duelling"/>
      <Help:Keyword keyword="fight"/>
      <Help:Keyword keyword="fighting"/>
    </Help:Keywords>
    <Core:Properties>
      <Core:Property property="revisions">
         (\{ 1135365937, "-", "SYNC" \})
      </Core:Property>
    </Core:Properties>
    <Ur:UrObject/>
  </Help:Node>
</object>
