<object clone="/usr/SkotOS/obj/help" owner="SkotOS">
  <Help:Node title="General Concepts: Communicate">
    <Log:Description>
       <br/>Title: Communicate<br/> Important Commands: ', ", whisper, ooc<br/> Syntax: '[message], "[message], whisper to Jane 'message, ooc '[message]<br/><br/> When you're participating in a Skotos game or Theatre, you'll normally be communicating In Character (IC).<br/> {? | $(udat.chatmode) |As long as you're in chatmode, you can just type what you want to say and it'll appear to everyone else in the room. You can toggle chatmode by typing /CHATMODE. In chatmode, you can use other modes of expression by prefacing a verb with the "/" character.|To say something IC type ' or " followed by your message. Typing 'Greetings, friend!, would read as: You say, "Greetings, friend!"}<br/> To whisper, type $(udat.chatchar)WHISPER [TARGET] "[MESSAGE]". Typing whisper to Jane 'You are very lovely, Jane. would read as: "You whisper to Jane, 'You are very lovely Jane.'<br/> There are many other methods that you can use to communicate. Some common verbs are: $(udat.chatchar)SHOUT, $(udat.chatchar)SCREAM, $(udat.chatchar)EXCLAIM, $(udat.chatchar)ANNOUNCE, $(udat.chatchar)ASK, $(udat.chatchar)QUESTION, and $(udat.chatchar)MUMBLE. In addition, any of these types of speech can be used with a huge number of adverbs: BLANKLY, LONGINGLY, STIFFLY, QUIETLY, and DISAPPROVINGLY are a few examples. To get a list of potential adverbs, type $(udat.chatchar)[SPEECH VERB] [FIRST LETTER]. For example "$(udat.chatchar)shout m" would give you a list of all adverbs beginning with "m" that could be used with the SHOUT verb.<br/> When talking Out Of Character (OOC) you should make this clear by using the $(udat.chatchar)@OOC verb. For example: @ooc "I was just joking.<br/> {? equal | $(theatre.gameid) | Marrach |You may also read out-loud books with RECITE, and scrolls with RECITE, CHANT, CITE, INSTRUCT, SING, and ORATE. |In some games you can RECITE scrolls or books out loud. }-- see help recite. <br/><br/>See Also: Adverbs, Character, Emotion<br/>
    </Log:Description>
    <Help:Keywords>
      <Help:Keyword keyword="communicate"/>
      <Help:Keyword keyword="communication"/>
      <Help:Keyword keyword="new"/>
    </Help:Keywords>
    <Core:Properties>
      <Core:Property property="revisions">
         (\{ 1081633138, "ocannie", "E" \})
      </Core:Property>
    </Core:Properties>
    <Ur:UrObject/>
  </Help:Node>
</object>
