<object clone="/usr/SkotOS/obj/help" owner="SkotOS">
  <Help:Node title="General Concepts: Consent">
    <Log:Description>
       <br/>Title: Consent<br/> Commands: Accept, Allow, Deny, Offer, Refuse<br/> <br/> In real life if a stranger moves to hug you, you can move away or block their action. Equally, you can allow your friends to embrace you as well as accept any gifts they may offer. The same applies to many of Skotos' Theatres - no character can approach you, hug you, or give you items unless you consent. <br/> If you try to do something physical that requires consent, like hug or kiss or sit by [someone], you'll be told it requires consent. The person you are approaching must either $(udat.chatchar)ALLOW [YOUR NAME] or $(udat.chatchar)DENY [YOUR NAME].<br/> You can customize whether to always deny someone consent or always allow it for these physical approaches. To always allow someone consent, type $(udat.chatchar)CONSENT ALLOW [NAME]. To always deny someone consent, type $(udat.chatchar)CONSENT DENY [NAME]. To totally remove someone from your consent list, type $(udat.chatchar)CONSENT REMOVE [NAME]. To see your current consent list, type $(udat.chatchar)CONSENT LIST. <br/> Trading items works similarly to physical consent. To offer an item to someone, type $(udat.chatchar)OFFER [ITEM] TO [NAME]. The player you are offering the item to must then type either $(udat.chatchar)ACCEPT [ITEM] or $(udat.chatchar)REFUSE [ITEM]. Unlike physical consent, you can not permanently put someone in a "accept-item" or a "refuse-item" list, since accepting an object takes a physical action. <br/><br/> See Also: Manipulation, Proximity<br/>
    </Log:Description>
    <Help:Keywords>
      <Help:Keyword keyword="allow"/>
      <Help:Keyword keyword="consent"/>
      <Help:Keyword keyword="deny"/>
      <Help:Keyword keyword="permission"/>
    </Help:Keywords>
    <Core:Properties>
      <Core:Property property="revisions">
         (\{ 1135365940, "-", "SYNC" \})
      </Core:Property>
    </Core:Properties>
    <Ur:UrObject/>
  </Help:Node>
</object>
