<object clone="/usr/SkotOS/obj/help" owner="SID">
  <Help:Node title="General Concepts: Courier">
    <Log:Description>
       <br/>Title: Courier CNPCs<br/> {? equal | $(theatre.gameid) | Marrach | Important Commands: ask<br/><br/> Couriers and Pages in Castle Marrach carry messages. You can request blank scrolls and give written scrolls to them. They will give the scroll to its intended recipient when they next see that person. Couriers will be used in the following examples.<br/> As with all CNPCs, you must $(udat.chatchar)ASK a courier to receive the object he gives out: "$(udat.chatchar)ask courier for scroll".<br/> Once you have a scroll, you can do number of things with it. You can $(udat.chatchar)WRITE a message on the scroll ($(udat.chatchar)write on my scroll "I hear there's a poet's convocation at 7 bells!"); you can $(udat.chatchar)ADDRESS the scroll to someone ($(udat.chatchar)address scroll to launfal); and you can $(udat.chatchar)SIGN the scroll ($(udat.chatchar)sign scroll). You can choose to include a salutation with your signature ($(udat.chatchar)sign scroll "Hatefully Yours")<br/>Note: If you are holding more than one scroll, you may specify which scroll to interact with by specifying the number ($(udat.chatchar)write on my [number] scroll. <br/>  If you'd like to write longer scrolls, you can use the write command multiple times. They'll continue to be appended. Just be sure that you sign your scroll last, as writing will erase any previous signatures. <br/>Note: You can only append to your own scroll; writing on a scroll written by someone else will erase it first.<br/>When you're all done, simply return the scroll ($(udat.chatchar)give scroll to courier). The next time the courier comes across the intended recipient of the letter, it will be handed over.<br/> If a courier gives you a scroll, you'll want to $(udat.chatchar)READ it ($(udat.chatchar)read scroll). Scrolls can be recycled! Just $(udat.chatchar)ERASE the old text ($(udat.chatchar)erase scroll) and then you can write your own message!<br/>You may also RECITE, CHANT, CITE, INSTRUCT, SING, and ORATE scrolls, which will read them out loud. <br/>The commands @compose and @readall can make manipulating multiple scrolls, and composing scrolls easier. These features are available in all of the standard browsers, however you must be allowing pop-ups in order to use them.<br/>| <br/> Some larger Skotos games include couriers who will transmit written messages to other characters.<br/>} <br/> See Also: CNPCs, address, write, sign, erase, read, recite<br/>
    </Log:Description>
    <Help:Keywords>
      <Help:Keyword keyword="courier"/>
      <Help:Keyword keyword="couriers"/>
      <Help:Keyword keyword="scroll"/>
      <Help:Keyword keyword="scrolls"/>
    </Help:Keywords>
    <Core:Properties>
      <Core:Property property="revisions">
         (\{ 1101052574, "lady_luminous_of_the_shadows", "X", 1108319352, "lady_luminous_of_the_shadows", "E", 1108319651, "lady_luminous_of_the_shadows", "E", 1108319695, "lady_luminous_of_the_shadows", "E", 1108320310, "lady_luminous_of_the_shadows", "E", 1108320510, "lady_luminous_of_the_shadows", "E", 1108320590, "lady_luminous_of_the_shadows", "E" \})
      </Core:Property>
    </Core:Properties>
    <Ur:UrObject/>
  </Help:Node>
</object>
