<object clone="/usr/SkotOS/obj/help" owner="SkotOS">
  <Help:Node title="General Concepts: Fun">
    <Log:Description>
       <br/>Title: Fun<br/><br/> We are all here for the same reason, presumably, and that is to have fun. Sometimes it is easier said than done in a new unfamiliar environment. {? equal | $(theatre.gameid) | Marrach | First and foremost, as a displaced soul in Castle Marrach, it is perfectly logical that your character is perhaps as clueless as you might be about the setting, theme and activities. It is good to play up the newness and the learning process. Exploration is key. Every room has a full description and items to examine. NPCs are roaming the halls, other StoryPlayers are venturing out for the first time just like you.<br/> Take advantage of the introduction process. Meet people, try out verbs and their accompanying adverbs. Explore, read scrolls and converse with others. Ask questions, look for clues, learn the inner workings of the castle. You are an explorer discovering a new land. There will be StoryPlotters and StoryHosts to provide plots and plot hooks, but you are free to discover interesting facets of the castle on your own. There are history, mystery, and secrets here, all waiting to be found. | But, don't worry about it. Every single person in a Skotos game or Theatre has been new at some time, and many of them will probably be happy to help you out.<br/> Meet new people and talk to them. Ask questions. Explore your environment. Even the smallest Theatres tend to have a few nooks and crannies. As you explore, you'll discover there's a lot of fun to be had in whatever virtual world you happen to be exploring.} <br/><br/> See Also: Character, Roleplaying, Theme<br/>
    </Log:Description>
    <Help:Keywords>
      <Help:Keyword keyword="bore"/>
      <Help:Keyword keyword="bored"/>
      <Help:Keyword keyword="boredom"/>
      <Help:Keyword keyword="boring"/>
      <Help:Keyword keyword="fun"/>
    </Help:Keywords>
    <Core:Properties>
      <Core:Property property="revisions">
         (\{ 1081632725, "ocannie", "E" \})
      </Core:Property>
    </Core:Properties>
    <Ur:UrObject/>
  </Help:Node>
</object>
