<object clone="/usr/SkotOS/obj/help" owner="SkotOS">
  <Help:Node title="General Concepts: Gait">
    <Log:Description>
       <br/>Title: Logging and Autologging<br/><br/>To log your activities in Castle Marrach there are different commands for each of the main clients supported by the game.<br/><br/>Internet Explorer: If you are using Microsoft Internet Explorer (which supports the 'Alice' client for Castle Marrach) hover your mouse over the central text window of the Castle Marrach client, and right-click. This will pop up a window which will prompt you for a directory and filename where you can save this session's log.<br/><br/>Firefox: If you are using Firefox (which supports the 'Zealotry' client for Castle Marrach), you can select Logging from the File menu embedded within the Castle Marrach client window.<br/><br/>Many players prefer to give their logfiles a regular naming scheme, such as 'character-day-starttime.txt' so they will easily recognize the contents of their logfiles at a glance.<br/><br/>Firefox/Zealotry also supports Autologging, which will automatically start logging each time you connect. When you first select Autologging, you will be asked the directory where you will store future logfiles. However, you will not have the option of what to name your files this way. They will be automatically given a filename such as autolog.Marrach.(charname).(timestamp). (The timestamp is the number of seconds since 1 Jan 1970.)<br/><br/>
    </Log:Description>
    <Help:Keywords>
      <Help:Keyword keyword="autolog"/>
      <Help:Keyword keyword="autologging"/>
      <Help:Keyword keyword="log"/>
      <Help:Keyword keyword="logging"/>
      <Help:Keyword keyword="logs"/>
    </Help:Keywords>
    <Core:Properties>
      <Core:Property property="revisions">
         (\{ 1164092759, "garethbeaumains", "E", 1164092773, "garethbeaumains", "E", 1164092785, "garethbeaumains", "E", 1164092800, "garethbeaumains", "E", 1164092834, "garethbeaumains", "E", 1164092854, "garethbeaumains", "E", 1164093165, "garethbeaumains", "E", 1164093187, "garethbeaumains", "E", 1164093200, "garethbeaumains", "E", 1164093209, "garethbeaumains", "E", 1164093216, "garethbeaumains", "E", 1164094452, "garethbeaumains", "E", 1164095586, "garethbeaumains", "E", 1164095825, "garethbeaumains", "E", 1164095910, "garethbeaumains", "E" \})
      </Core:Property>
    </Core:Properties>
    <Ur:UrObject/>
  </Help:Node>
</object>
