<object clone="/usr/SkotOS/obj/help" owner="SkotOS">
  <Help:Node title="General Concepts: Roleplaying">
    <Log:Description>
       Title: Role-playing<br/><br/> Role-playing (and having fun) is what we are here to do! For new role-players, it may take time to learn how to role-play well, but in a sense role-playing is very similar to the game "let’s pretend" from your youth -- close your eyes, imagine who you want to pretend to be, and then do it!<br/> Good and great role-playing can be a subjective determination, but there are some key steps that many good role-players practice. First, in an online setting these players spend the time learning what tools they have at their disposal to better help them convey their character. Second, these players allow their imagination to run wild and take the time to think about:<br/><br/> * What is the theme of the gaming session?<br/> * Who/what kind of character would they like to play?<br/> * How does this character physically look? <br/> * What is this character’s history, mannerisms, likes, dislikes, values, and beliefs?<br/> * What is this character’s goal(s)? <br/> * How far (or not) will the character go in order to achieve the goal(s)?<br/><br/> Third, good role-players tend to consistently respond to interactions and situations with other characters In Character (IC) -- and are able to recognize what types of significant interactions and situations might affect and/or change their character’s personality. They allow the character to evolve or devolve as the case may be. <br/> Finally, a respected trait of great role-players is their ability to recognize the difference between Fantasy and Real Life. They know the main reason anyone is here is to have fun and they can have silly, dramatic or intense role-play sessions without overstepping the boundaries of courtesy and respect to the other players behind the other characters.<br/> Over time and with experience and effort anyone can be become a good or great role-player.<br/><br/> See Topics: Character, Fun, IC, Theme<br/>
    </Log:Description>
    <Help:Keywords>
      <Help:Keyword keyword="roleplay"/>
      <Help:Keyword keyword="roleplaying"/>
    </Help:Keywords>
    <Core:Properties>
      <Core:Property property="revisions">
         (\{ 1081636042, "ocannie", "E" \})
      </Core:Property>
    </Core:Properties>
    <Ur:UrObject/>
  </Help:Node>
</object>
