<object clone="/obj/properties" owner="TextIF">
  <Core:PropertyContainer>
    <Ur:UrObject/>
    <Core:PCProperties>
      <Core:Property property="page">
         "\<h1 style=\\"text-align: center;\\"\>About MIki\</h1\>\<sbr/\>MIki is currently in \<span style=\\"font-style: italic;\\"\>alpha stage\</span\> which essentially means it has just stepped out from the dark, musky laboratory into the light and sort of hopes it won't screw anything major up. But we all know it will. The time it will remain\\"alpha\\" is entirely up to you. The more people who play around with it, the less time before it is declared more stable. The amount of interest also dictates the amount of effort I put into it. If nobody cares, I won't bother, but if people do care, I will.\<sbr/\>\<sbr/\>\<span style=\\"font-weight: bold;\\"\>What is MIki?\</span\>\<sbr/\>MIki is a Wiki, like TWiki. A Wiki is a \\"web-based collaborative tool\\" which allows users to easily add pages and modify content. It keeps track of who did what when, and allows \\"reversion\\" to previous revisions. \<span style=\\"font-style: italic;\\"\>MIki \</span\>does not even have revision control yet, and it's probably pushing it, calling it a Wiki even, but the core philosophy is there and the heart's in the right place. And with time, it'll grow up into a peer among peers, I'm sure.\<sbr/\>\<sbr/\>\<span style=\\"font-weight: bold;\\"\>Why the name \\"MIki\\"?\</span\>\<sbr/\>MIki is \\"Merry-Wiki\\" smushed into one word. That's it.\<sbr/\>\<sbr/\>\<span style=\\"font-weight: bold;\\"\>What cool stuff can it do?\</span\>\<sbr/\>It can do WYSIWYG, which is pretty cool. But it can also do inline SAM and, thus, Merry.\<sbr/\>\<sbr/\>\<span style=\\"font-weight: bold;\\"\>Can we use it for secret stuff?\</span\>\<sbr/\>If, by secret, you are talking about \\"stuff you only want staff to see\\",then YES. That's exactly what it's for. If you mean to exclude others on staff, then no, unfortunately. I won't pretend that the system can hide stuff from staffers when, with very basic Merry knowledge, anyone could extract that information anyway. See [Privacy and security].\<sbr/\>\<sbr/\>\<span style=\\"font-weight: bold;\\"\>Is it going to be available as a player-wiki also?\</span\>\<sbr/\>Probably not. MIki is meant to be a staff resource mainly targeting staff-related issues. There is no security built into it to exclude specific people from viewing specific webs, which means \\"if you can see one page, you can see 'em all.\\" Additionally, as MIki consumes game resources, it should remain a low-profile tool so as to not cause unnecessary lag to the game.\<sbr/\>\<span style=\\"font-weight: bold;\\"\>\<span style=\\"font-weight: bold;\\"\>\<span style=\\"font-weight: bold;\\"\>\</span\>\</span\>\<sbr/\>\</span\>"
      </Core:Property>
      <Core:Property property="reads">2</Core:Property>
      <Core:Property property="refback">
         ([ "index_":1 ])
      </Core:Property>
      <Core:Property property="revisions">
         (\{ 1144052057, "-", "SYNC", 1146338684, "zwoc", "E" \})
      </Core:Property>
    </Core:PCProperties>
    <Notes:Notes/>
  </Core:PropertyContainer>
</object>
