<object clone="/base/obj/thing" owner="SID">
  <Base:Thing>
    <Ur:UrObject/>
    <Base:Bulk immobile="false" mass="0.3" density="1.1"/>
    <Base:Container flexible="false" transparent-container="false" public-container="false" tight="false" capacity="0" maxweight="0"/>
    <Base:Misc gender="neuter" volition="false" weapon="false" default_stance="none" combinable="false" discrete="false" by_weight="false" tight="false" scriptrunner="false">
      <Base:Edible value="false"/>
      <Base:Potable value="false"/>
      <Base:DrinkMessageFirst/>
      <Base:DrinkMessageThird/>
      <Base:Transparency value="false"/>
      <Base:Unsafe value="false"/>
      <Base:Safe value="false"/>
      <Base:ClothesExpected value="false"/>
      <Base:DieMessageFirst/>
      <Base:DieMessageThird/>
    </Base:Misc>
    <Base:Details>
      <Base:Detail id="default" prime="true" def="false" abstract="false" hidden="false" luminosity="0" targetable_in_dark="false" plural="false">
        <Base:Preposition close="false" against="false" under="false" on="false" inside="false" near="false" over="false" behind="false" before="false" beside="false"/>
        <Base:Names>
          <Base:SNames>
            <Base:SName sname="text"/>
          </Base:SNames>
          <Base:PNames>
            <Base:PName pname="texts"/>
          </Base:PNames>
        </Base:Names>
        <Base:Adjectives/>
        <Base:Descriptions>
          <Base:Description type="brief">text</Base:Description>
        </Base:Descriptions>
        <Base:Exit door="false" closed="false" locked="false" never_obvious="false" obvious_when_open="false" hidden_when_closed="false" separate="false" self-locking="false" deadbolt="false"/>
        <Base:Climbable/>
      </Base:Detail>
    </Base:Details>
    <Base:Clothing>
      <Base:SingleWear value="false"/>
    </Base:Clothing>
    <Base:Crafting see_level="0" do_level="0" time="0" attention="false" held="false">
      <Base:Ingredients/>
      <Base:Tools/>
      <Base:CraftVerbs/>
    </Base:Crafting>
    <Base:InitialContents/>
    <Base:InitialProperties>
      <Base:InitialProperty property="trait:page00">
         "THE CODE DUELLO"
      </Base:InitialProperty>
      <Base:InitialProperty property="trait:page01">
         "THE CODE DUELLO\<br/\>\<br/\>CONTENTS\<br/\>\<br/\>2. - Introduction\<br/\>3. - How Duels Are Begun\<br/\>4. - When Duelling Is Impermissible\<br/\>5. - Conditions For A Duel\<br/\>6. - On Seconds\<br/\>7. - Sanction For Formal Duels\<br/\>8. - Putting One's Affairs In Order\<br/\>9. - Beginning The Duel\<br/\>10. - The Duel Itself\<br/\>11. - Finish Of The Duel\<br/\>12. - Practice\<br/\>13. - Informal And Unsanctioned Duels\<br/\>14. - Masters Of The Court Of Honor\<br/\>15. - A Toast\<br/\>16. - Updates\<br/\>"
      </Base:InitialProperty>
      <Base:InitialProperty property="trait:page02">
         "“Never draw your sword without good reason; never sheath it without your honor.”\<br/\>\<br/\> INTRODUCTION\<br/\>\<br/\> Inhabitants of Castle Marrach may decide to resolve their serious disputes by a duel (also known as an encounter, or passage of arms). A duel is one-on-one combat between persons of honor, with a specific set of conditions agreed to by both parties. Duelling is governed by the Duelling Code, sometimes known as the Code Duello. Duels are fought to express, protect and restore one’s honor, the honor of someone one feels bound to protect, or (unofficially) to build a reputation as a duelist. A duel is only possible when there has been an insult or a slight to someone’s honor. Any word, action, intention, or gesture, which injures the self-esteem, sensibility, or reputation of another, is for this person an affront. Duels are most emphatically not acts of revenge or retribution – at least not according to the Duelling Code. Duelling is sometimes considered a ceremony of the cult of honor, an entirely unofficial, un-organized but real group nebulously composed of all persons with the right – and the duty – of demanding satisfaction in a duel. Allegations of misconduct by prospective or actual duelists and seconds, with regard to their participation in a duel, may be inquired into by the Masters of the Court of Honor, three respected, perceptive and impartial persons. These Masters are skilled with weapons, fully conversant with the rules, precedents, and spirit of the Duelling Code, and have some not-well-defined authority in the area of personal honor. If someone issues a challenge and is refused, the Court of Honor can be appealed to for a ruling on the honor of the refusal. The Court also answers questions touching on the manner and practice of duelling; their decisions may be appealed to the Lord Chancellor. Violations of the spirit and rules of the Duelling Code will (if detected and reported) result in censure by (at least) the Masters of the Court of Honor. Appeals to the Queen may be made regarding the decisions of the Lord Chancellor. Within Castle Marrach, the Queen, the Lord Chancellor, the Lord Marshal, the Lord Treasurer, and the Lord Chamberlain are the premier honor lords of the Court."
      </Base:InitialProperty>
      <Base:InitialProperty property="trait:page03">
         "HOW DUELS ARE BEGUN\<br/\>\<br/\> Two persons have or imagine a quarrel upon some point. One of them, feeling their honor to be insufferably transgressed upon, says something like, “Sir, a gentle person cannot accept that insult” – there are any number of acceptable phrasings for the challenge. Persons issuing a challenge are termed the ‘injured’ party or person, as they claim to have suffered some damage to their reputation, veracity, pedigree, person, etc; they are also said to have ‘requested’ or ‘demanded’ satisfaction. Being manhandled without permission is often considered the minimum insult that will lead to a duel, but each person is the best judge of his or her own honor. For a challenge to be made, the challenger must consider whoever is challenged to be worthy of it – specifically, in a position to provide satisfaction in a duel. Stating that one will not issue a challenge due to the unworthy nature of the person giving offense is tantamount to saying the person is not honorable (and hence not worthy of attending Her Majesty’s court, as an honored guest, courtier, knight, noble, or otherwise). Challenges need not be delivered in person. In fact, if the challenge does not follow immediately upon the act that gave offense, the offended party (i.e., the challenger) should obtain the services of one or more seconds, to convey his or her challenge – rather than delivering it in person. Challenges may not be delivered in writing; written challenges have many opportunities for error. The seconds may convey written statements by the principals, but they themselves must confirm that the challenge has been received, and whether it has been accepted. The challenged party may accept or reject the challenge. If the challenge is accepted, then from that point until the duel is fought the two parties to the dispute should avoid each other socially. They are both parties to the dispute, in rather the same sense that litigants in a court of law are parties to a suit."
      </Base:InitialProperty>
      <Base:InitialProperty property="trait:page04">
         "WHEN DUELLING IS IMPERMISSIBLE\<br/\>\<br/\>The Queen or Her Lords may forbid persons to make or receive challenges for some period of time, or from some person, or from a category of persons, etc. Encounters with persons of widely (OOC: OB denizens challenging Lords, for instance)different social rank are possible, but may result in loss of favor or even punishment for one or both parties; certainly persons of high rank are under no obligation to accept challenges from those of a widely lower rank. Persons married to each other; persons not physically fit; and persons in close family relation to each other may not enter into a duel. The Queen may from time to time issue restrictions upon encounters by her subjects; for instance, in time of war, duelling may be forbidden entirely."
      </Base:InitialProperty>
      <Base:InitialProperty property="trait:page05">
         "CONDITIONS FOR A DUEL\<br/\>\<br/\>There are several conditions to be met before a duel can be fought:\<br/\>\<br/\> Approval or sanction by the authorities is not required; however, duelling without approval can result in social disfavor, censure by the Court of Honor, or actual punishment (loss of status, position, rank, or privileges). The consent of both parties is absolutely required. Deadly combat without the consent of all parties is regarded as murder. Seconds or friends must make at least a pro forma attempt at reconcilement, and must arrange the conditions of the duel. The offer and acceptance of an apology brings the challenge to an end. A delay of at least one day (from the challenge to the actual combat); duels fought with less than a day’s delay are viewed with disfavor. Challenges must be issued or communicated within two days of the challenging party becoming aware of the offense (which might, of course, be years after the commission of the offense itself). If more time passes, the nature of the offense cannot have been unbearable, and the affront is said to have expired."
      </Base:InitialProperty>
      <Base:InitialProperty property="trait:page06">
         "ON SECONDS\<br/\>\<br/\> No duel may be fought in Castle Marrach without at least one second for each party. A second is some other person, also capable of providing satisfaction, who agrees to act on behalf of one (and only one) of the parties to a duel. The terms ‘representative’ or ‘friend’ are sometimes also used to designate seconds. The second has two duties: to the person he or she is seconding, and to the Duelling Code. This censure can fall equally heavily – or in some cases, more heavily – upon the seconds. If a second cannot not both fairly represent his or her principal, and also the Duelling Code, he or she should withdraw, and the duel should be re-arranged with a new second. There is no requirement that a second actually be a friend, or even an acquaintance, of his or her principal. Persons should not serve as seconds if there would be some substantial conflict of interest involved; also, the spouses, parents, and children of a duelist should not serve as his or her second."
      </Base:InitialProperty>
      <Base:InitialProperty property="trait:page07">
         "SANCTION FOR FORMAL DUELS\<br/\>\<br/\>Each party to the dispute chooses a second (presumably a friend); the seconds call together upon some competent authority—an honor lord of the Queen’s Court, or the Queen herself. The Chamberlain is most often conveniently available for this, but the Chancellor, the Lord Marshal, or the Lord Treasurer are each also empowered to sanction duels. The Chamberlain (or other ‘sanctioning’ authority): \<br/\> -- asks the seconds who the parties to the duel are; asks whether any attempt has been made for reconcilement; \<br/\> -- ensures the parties are not barred from duelling (due to hierarchical, social, legal, physical, etc. conditions); \<br/\> -- enquires and consents as to the form of the duel (the weapons to be used, any strange variant rules, and the desired outcome—death or wounding, or some number of wounds, a cry for quarter, or some other measurable or detectable finish); \<br/\> -- enquires and consents to any ‘victory’ or ‘defeat’ conditions involving Castle Marrach’s court or society (i.e., changes to official positions); \<br/\> -- enquires and consents to the time and place of the encounter and issues instructions to prepare the site if need be; \<br/\> -- instructs and charges the seconds to see that no chicanery takes place, and to carry out their duties as representatives of the Court of Honor at the duel; \<br/\> -- instructs and charges the seconds to contact an authority as soon as possible if there is some obstacle to the duel proceeding, or if one of the parties wishes to withdraw; formally approves the duel, with the restrictions agreed to previously; \<br/\> -- advises the seconds to have the principals put their affairs in order; causes some form of notice of the duel to be made ‘public.’ This notice will include the names of the participants, and their seconds; the time and date of the duel; and some of the elements of form. \<br/\>\<br/\>Persons may wish, as suggested, to put their affairs in order prior to taking part in a duel. They should certainly not carry items of great personal value into a duel, as there is a chance they may lose them if the duel is lost."
      </Base:InitialProperty>
      <Base:InitialProperty property="trait:page08">
         "PUTTING ONE'S AFFAIRS IN ORDER\<br/\>\<br/\> Persons wishing to produce registered wills should arrange to have their testament taken down and filed with a Court Clerk (or the Royal Archivist). Other wills and testaments, not filed in the archives, may not be enforced by the Chancery. The Court Clerk may also be willing to hold messages for delivery after a person’s demise."
      </Base:InitialProperty>
      <Base:InitialProperty property="trait:page09">
         "BEGINNING THE DUEL\<br/\>\<br/\> If the parties to the quarrel, and their seconds, are present at the time and place agreed, someone will bring weapons to the seconds (although the parties may possess and use weapons of their own, if they agree). The seconds and all other parties should avoid standing in the “middle” before the duel begins, and the armed duelists should stand in the “middle of the area, room, or whatever. The seconds may (or may not) keep things organized, advise spectators to step back, etc.; they should (but don’t have to) ask the duelists if they can yet be reconciled, etc.; but their duties are not enforced – they must merely be present in the room. Once the duelists have taken up their positions [command: duel name], and each saluted the other with their weapons, the duel begins, and cannot be interrupted by the spectators; the spectators and seconds should not enter the “middle” of the area. Duelists may, if they wish, conduct a ‘full salute’ – a bow to the audience, followed by a salute to the opponent. The duel as an affair of honor still begins from when both duelists have saluted their opponent."
      </Base:InitialProperty>
      <Base:InitialProperty property="trait:page10">
         "THE DUEL ITSELF\<br/\>\<br/\> During the duel, the combatants must remain in the room, but they may move about the room. Duels are normally assumed to be conducted with the generic sword; some persons possess and may use rapiers, sabers, cutlasses, short swords, backswords, schiavone, small swords, two-handed swords, bastard swords, etc. The Court of Honor can decide if the use of unequal or unusual weapons in a duel is a violation of the Duelling Code. The Court of Honor might admit other weapons that might be become available; these might include the foil, scimitar, single-stick, great stick, etc.\<br/\>\<br/\> In a duel to first blood, a single wound ends the bout and the duel itself. In duels of a more serious nature, the fighting ceases momentarily when a wound is received; the seconds may wish to enquire if the principals can or wish to continue. If a continuation is agreed to, the duellists re-engage [duel and salute as usual; a duel to the death might thus consist of as many as eight bouts]."
      </Base:InitialProperty>
      <Base:InitialProperty property="trait:page11">
         "FINISH OF THE DUEL\<br/\>\<br/\> In a formal duel, the ‘passage of arms’ is completed when either the agreed-upon conditions are met, one of the combatants surrenders [command: surrender], one of the combatants leaves the room, or both of the seconds agree to end the duel [although this is not enforced by the system]. [A bad connection should not result in a lost duel. The seconds are responsible for observing their principals; if they think too much time has gone by without any communication, they may wish to call out some notice of this. Honorable duelists should not take advantage of ‘inconvenienced’ opponents in this situation.]"
      </Base:InitialProperty>
      <Base:InitialProperty property="trait:page12">
         "PRACTICE\<br/\>\<br/\> For the practice of swordplay within the Castle, the practice room, armory, and various open courtyards are normally employed. Practice may also take place in the guard rooms, the quarters of the Winter Watch, or the personal room of any guest. ‘Blunted’ or ‘rebated’ weapons are normally used in practice. Opponents move to the middle of the room, salute, and begin; no seconds are required. In a practice bout conducted with blunt or rebated weapons, the duelists may acknowledge a hit (“Your point, ser”) by extending their empty hand, palm uppermost, to their opponent [OOC: possible command: “extend my left hand briefly”]. Challenges from newly-arrived guests may be honorably refused until they prove themselves able to give and receive satisfaction — “Duelling is for those worthy of it, my dear”; however, non-fatal duelling is certainly possible before then, if only as practice."
      </Base:InitialProperty>
      <Base:InitialProperty property="trait:page13">
         "INFORMAL AND UNSANCTIONED DUELS\<br/\>\<br/\> If an immediate or sub rosa duel is felt to be needed, the parties to the dispute should still choose seconds. The seconds negotiate the nature of the duel – when and where, and to what lengths; they also will have to obtain weapons by some method or other. An informal or unsanctioned duel may incur the wrath of the Queen’s officials, or the Court of Honor, or both, or neither. Much depends on the circumstances, and on how much the affair deviated from fair and traditional duelling. Combat without seconds is almost never recognized as a proper duel; it is no more or no less than combat, proper in some circumstances but not in others. The Queen and the Court of Honor do not look with favor on common murder."
      </Base:InitialProperty>
      <Base:InitialProperty property="trait:page14">
         "MASTERS OF THE COURT OF HONOR\<br/\>\<br/\>Currently, the Masters of the Court of Honor are:\<br/\>\<br/\>Lord Bernier;\<br/\>Sir Anselm; and\<br/\>Dame Petronille.\<br/\>"
      </Base:InitialProperty>
      <Base:InitialProperty property="trait:page15">
         "\\"Stand now and raise your glasses, let us by the world be seen,\<br/\> Good health and heaven's grace attend you, VIVIENNE OUR QUEEN.\\""
      </Base:InitialProperty>
      <Base:InitialProperty property="trait:page16">
         "UPDATES\<br/\>\<br/\>As rulings are made by Her Majesty or the Court of Honor respecting the conduct of encounters of honor, the text of this book will be mysteriously updated."
      </Base:InitialProperty>
    </Base:InitialProperties>
    <Core:Properties>
      <Core:Property property="skill:fatigue">1.0</Core:Property>
      <Core:Property property="trait:page00">
         "THE CODE DUELLO"
      </Core:Property>
      <Core:Property property="trait:page01">
         "THE CODE DUELLO\<br/\>\<br/\>CONTENTS\<br/\>\<br/\>2. - Introduction\<br/\>3. - How Duels Are Begun\<br/\>4. - When Duelling Is Impermissible\<br/\>5. - Conditions For A Duel\<br/\>6. - On Seconds\<br/\>7. - Sanction For Formal Duels\<br/\>8. - Putting One's Affairs In Order\<br/\>9. - Beginning The Duel\<br/\>10. - The Duel Itself\<br/\>11. - Finish Of The Duel\<br/\>12. - Practice\<br/\>13. - Informal And Unsanctioned Duels\<br/\>14. - Masters Of The Court Of Honor\<br/\>15. - A Toast\<br/\>16. - Updates\<br/\>"
      </Core:Property>
      <Core:Property property="trait:page02">
         "“Never draw your sword without good reason; never sheath it without your honor.”\<br/\>\<br/\> INTRODUCTION\<br/\>\<br/\> Inhabitants of Castle Marrach may decide to resolve their serious disputes by a duel (also known as an encounter, or passage of arms). A duel is one-on-one combat between persons of honor, with a specific set of conditions agreed to by both parties. Duelling is governed by the Duelling Code, sometimes known as the Code Duello. Duels are fought to express, protect and restore one’s honor, the honor of someone one feels bound to protect, or (unofficially) to build a reputation as a duelist. A duel is only possible when there has been an insult or a slight to someone’s honor. Any word, action, intention, or gesture, which injures the self-esteem, sensibility, or reputation of another, is for this person an affront. Duels are most emphatically not acts of revenge or retribution – at least not according to the Duelling Code. Duelling is sometimes considered a ceremony of the cult of honor, an entirely unofficial, un-organized but real group nebulously composed of all persons with the right – and the duty – of demanding satisfaction in a duel. Allegations of misconduct by prospective or actual duelists and seconds, with regard to their participation in a duel, may be inquired into by the Masters of the Court of Honor, three respected, perceptive and impartial persons. These Masters are skilled with weapons, fully conversant with the rules, precedents, and spirit of the Duelling Code, and have some not-well-defined authority in the area of personal honor. If someone issues a challenge and is refused, the Court of Honor can be appealed to for a ruling on the honor of the refusal. The Court also answers questions touching on the manner and practice of duelling; their decisions may be appealed to the Lord Chancellor. Violations of the spirit and rules of the Duelling Code will (if detected and reported) result in censure by (at least) the Masters of the Court of Honor. Appeals to the Queen may be made regarding the decisions of the Lord Chancellor. Within Castle Marrach, the Queen, the Lord Chancellor, the Lord Marshal, the Lord Treasurer, and the Lord Chamberlain are the premier honor lords of the Court."
      </Core:Property>
      <Core:Property property="trait:page03">
         "HOW DUELS ARE BEGUN\<br/\>\<br/\> Two persons have or imagine a quarrel upon some point. One of them, feeling their honor to be insufferably transgressed upon, says something like, “Sir, a gentle person cannot accept that insult” – there are any number of acceptable phrasings for the challenge. Persons issuing a challenge are termed the ‘injured’ party or person, as they claim to have suffered some damage to their reputation, veracity, pedigree, person, etc; they are also said to have ‘requested’ or ‘demanded’ satisfaction. Being manhandled without permission is often considered the minimum insult that will lead to a duel, but each person is the best judge of his or her own honor. For a challenge to be made, the challenger must consider whoever is challenged to be worthy of it – specifically, in a position to provide satisfaction in a duel. Stating that one will not issue a challenge due to the unworthy nature of the person giving offense is tantamount to saying the person is not honorable (and hence not worthy of attending Her Majesty’s court, as an honored guest, courtier, knight, noble, or otherwise). Challenges need not be delivered in person. In fact, if the challenge does not follow immediately upon the act that gave offense, the offended party (i.e., the challenger) should obtain the services of one or more seconds, to convey his or her challenge – rather than delivering it in person. Challenges may not be delivered in writing; written challenges have many opportunities for error. The seconds may convey written statements by the principals, but they themselves must confirm that the challenge has been received, and whether it has been accepted. The challenged party may accept or reject the challenge. If the challenge is accepted, then from that point until the duel is fought the two parties to the dispute should avoid each other socially. They are both parties to the dispute, in rather the same sense that litigants in a court of law are parties to a suit."
      </Core:Property>
      <Core:Property property="trait:page04">
         "WHEN DUELLING IS IMPERMISSIBLE\<br/\>\<br/\>The Queen or Her Lords may forbid persons to make or receive challenges for some period of time, or from some person, or from a category of persons, etc. Encounters with persons of widely (OOC: OB denizens challenging Lords, for instance)different social rank are possible, but may result in loss of favor or even punishment for one or both parties; certainly persons of high rank are under no obligation to accept challenges from those of a widely lower rank. Persons married to each other; persons not physically fit; and persons in close family relation to each other may not enter into a duel. The Queen may from time to time issue restrictions upon encounters by her subjects; for instance, in time of war, duelling may be forbidden entirely."
      </Core:Property>
      <Core:Property property="trait:page05">
         "CONDITIONS FOR A DUEL\<br/\>\<br/\>There are several conditions to be met before a duel can be fought:\<br/\>\<br/\> Approval or sanction by the authorities is not required; however, duelling without approval can result in social disfavor, censure by the Court of Honor, or actual punishment (loss of status, position, rank, or privileges). The consent of both parties is absolutely required. Deadly combat without the consent of all parties is regarded as murder. Seconds or friends must make at least a pro forma attempt at reconcilement, and must arrange the conditions of the duel. The offer and acceptance of an apology brings the challenge to an end. A delay of at least one day (from the challenge to the actual combat); duels fought with less than a day’s delay are viewed with disfavor. Challenges must be issued or communicated within two days of the challenging party becoming aware of the offense (which might, of course, be years after the commission of the offense itself). If more time passes, the nature of the offense cannot have been unbearable, and the affront is said to have expired."
      </Core:Property>
      <Core:Property property="trait:page06">
         "ON SECONDS\<br/\>\<br/\> No duel may be fought in Castle Marrach without at least one second for each party. A second is some other person, also capable of providing satisfaction, who agrees to act on behalf of one (and only one) of the parties to a duel. The terms ‘representative’ or ‘friend’ are sometimes also used to designate seconds. The second has two duties: to the person he or she is seconding, and to the Duelling Code. This censure can fall equally heavily – or in some cases, more heavily – upon the seconds. If a second cannot not both fairly represent his or her principal, and also the Duelling Code, he or she should withdraw, and the duel should be re-arranged with a new second. There is no requirement that a second actually be a friend, or even an acquaintance, of his or her principal. Persons should not serve as seconds if there would be some substantial conflict of interest involved; also, the spouses, parents, and children of a duelist should not serve as his or her second."
      </Core:Property>
      <Core:Property property="trait:page07">
         "SANCTION FOR FORMAL DUELS\<br/\>\<br/\>Each party to the dispute chooses a second (presumably a friend); the seconds call together upon some competent authority—an honor lord of the Queen’s Court, or the Queen herself. The Chamberlain is most often conveniently available for this, but the Chancellor, the Lord Marshal, or the Lord Treasurer are each also empowered to sanction duels. The Chamberlain (or other ‘sanctioning’ authority): \<br/\> -- asks the seconds who the parties to the duel are; asks whether any attempt has been made for reconcilement; \<br/\> -- ensures the parties are not barred from duelling (due to hierarchical, social, legal, physical, etc. conditions); \<br/\> -- enquires and consents as to the form of the duel (the weapons to be used, any strange variant rules, and the desired outcome—death or wounding, or some number of wounds, a cry for quarter, or some other measurable or detectable finish); \<br/\> -- enquires and consents to any ‘victory’ or ‘defeat’ conditions involving Castle Marrach’s court or society (i.e., changes to official positions); \<br/\> -- enquires and consents to the time and place of the encounter and issues instructions to prepare the site if need be; \<br/\> -- instructs and charges the seconds to see that no chicanery takes place, and to carry out their duties as representatives of the Court of Honor at the duel; \<br/\> -- instructs and charges the seconds to contact an authority as soon as possible if there is some obstacle to the duel proceeding, or if one of the parties wishes to withdraw; formally approves the duel, with the restrictions agreed to previously; \<br/\> -- advises the seconds to have the principals put their affairs in order; causes some form of notice of the duel to be made ‘public.’ This notice will include the names of the participants, and their seconds; the time and date of the duel; and some of the elements of form. \<br/\>\<br/\>Persons may wish, as suggested, to put their affairs in order prior to taking part in a duel. They should certainly not carry items of great personal value into a duel, as there is a chance they may lose them if the duel is lost."
      </Core:Property>
      <Core:Property property="trait:page08">
         "PUTTING ONE'S AFFAIRS IN ORDER\<br/\>\<br/\> Persons wishing to produce registered wills should arrange to have their testament taken down and filed with a Court Clerk (or the Royal Archivist). Other wills and testaments, not filed in the archives, may not be enforced by the Chancery. The Court Clerk may also be willing to hold messages for delivery after a person’s demise."
      </Core:Property>
      <Core:Property property="trait:page09">
         "BEGINNING THE DUEL\<br/\>\<br/\> If the parties to the quarrel, and their seconds, are present at the time and place agreed, someone will bring weapons to the seconds (although the parties may possess and use weapons of their own, if they agree). The seconds and all other parties should avoid standing in the “middle” before the duel begins, and the armed duelists should stand in the “middle of the area, room, or whatever. The seconds may (or may not) keep things organized, advise spectators to step back, etc.; they should (but don’t have to) ask the duelists if they can yet be reconciled, etc.; but their duties are not enforced – they must merely be present in the room. Once the duelists have taken up their positions [command: duel name], and each saluted the other with their weapons, the duel begins, and cannot be interrupted by the spectators; the spectators and seconds should not enter the “middle” of the area. Duelists may, if they wish, conduct a ‘full salute’ – a bow to the audience, followed by a salute to the opponent. The duel as an affair of honor still begins from when both duelists have saluted their opponent."
      </Core:Property>
      <Core:Property property="trait:page10">
         "THE DUEL ITSELF\<br/\>\<br/\> During the duel, the combatants must remain in the room, but they may move about the room. Duels are normally assumed to be conducted with the generic sword; some persons possess and may use rapiers, sabers, cutlasses, short swords, backswords, schiavone, small swords, two-handed swords, bastard swords, etc. The Court of Honor can decide if the use of unequal or unusual weapons in a duel is a violation of the Duelling Code. The Court of Honor might admit other weapons that might be become available; these might include the foil, scimitar, single-stick, great stick, etc.\<br/\>\<br/\> In a duel to first blood, a single wound ends the bout and the duel itself. In duels of a more serious nature, the fighting ceases momentarily when a wound is received; the seconds may wish to enquire if the principals can or wish to continue. If a continuation is agreed to, the duellists re-engage [duel and salute as usual; a duel to the death might thus consist of as many as eight bouts]."
      </Core:Property>
      <Core:Property property="trait:page11">
         "FINISH OF THE DUEL\<br/\>\<br/\> In a formal duel, the ‘passage of arms’ is completed when either the agreed-upon conditions are met, one of the combatants surrenders [command: surrender], one of the combatants leaves the room, or both of the seconds agree to end the duel [although this is not enforced by the system]. [A bad connection should not result in a lost duel. The seconds are responsible for observing their principals; if they think too much time has gone by without any communication, they may wish to call out some notice of this. Honorable duelists should not take advantage of ‘inconvenienced’ opponents in this situation.]"
      </Core:Property>
      <Core:Property property="trait:page12">
         "PRACTICE\<br/\>\<br/\> For the practice of swordplay within the Castle, the practice room, armory, and various open courtyards are normally employed. Practice may also take place in the guard rooms, the quarters of the Winter Watch, or the personal room of any guest. ‘Blunted’ or ‘rebated’ weapons are normally used in practice. Opponents move to the middle of the room, salute, and begin; no seconds are required. In a practice bout conducted with blunt or rebated weapons, the duelists may acknowledge a hit (“Your point, ser”) by extending their empty hand, palm uppermost, to their opponent [OOC: possible command: “extend my left hand briefly”]. Challenges from newly-arrived guests may be honorably refused until they prove themselves able to give and receive satisfaction — “Duelling is for those worthy of it, my dear”; however, non-fatal duelling is certainly possible before then, if only as practice."
      </Core:Property>
      <Core:Property property="trait:page13">
         "INFORMAL AND UNSANCTIONED DUELS\<br/\>\<br/\> If an immediate or sub rosa duel is felt to be needed, the parties to the dispute should still choose seconds. The seconds negotiate the nature of the duel – when and where, and to what lengths; they also will have to obtain weapons by some method or other. An informal or unsanctioned duel may incur the wrath of the Queen’s officials, or the Court of Honor, or both, or neither. Much depends on the circumstances, and on how much the affair deviated from fair and traditional duelling. Combat without seconds is almost never recognized as a proper duel; it is no more or no less than combat, proper in some circumstances but not in others. The Queen and the Court of Honor do not look with favor on common murder."
      </Core:Property>
      <Core:Property property="trait:page14">
         "MASTERS OF THE COURT OF HONOR\<br/\>\<br/\>Currently, the Masters of the Court of Honor are:\<br/\>\<br/\>Lord Bernier;\<br/\>Sir Anselm; and\<br/\>Dame Petronille.\<br/\>"
      </Core:Property>
      <Core:Property property="trait:page15">
         "\\"Stand now and raise your glasses, let us by the world be seen,\<br/\> Good health and heaven's grace attend you, VIVIENNE OUR QUEEN.\\""
      </Core:Property>
      <Core:Property property="trait:page16">
         "UPDATES\<br/\>\<br/\>As rulings are made by Her Majesty or the Court of Honor respecting the conduct of encounters of honor, the text of this book will be mysteriously updated."
      </Core:Property>
      <Core:Property property="volition">0</Core:Property>
    </Core:Properties>
    <Notes:Notes>
      <Notes:Category cat="QA" catstate="Open">
        <Notes:Note ix="971734080" state="Comment" user="michaelb">
           Basic manual for the Code Duello.
        </Notes:Note>
      </Notes:Category>
    </Notes:Notes>
  </Base:Thing>
</object>
