<object clone="/base/obj/thing" owner="SID">
  <Base:Thing>
    <Ur:UrObject/>
    <Base:Bulk immobile="false" mass="0.3" density="1.1"/>
    <Base:Container flexible="false" transparent-container="false" public-container="false" tight="false" capacity="0" maxweight="0"/>
    <Base:Misc gender="neuter" volition="false" weapon="false" default_stance="none" combinable="false" discrete="false" by_weight="false" tight="false" scriptrunner="false">
      <Base:Edible value="false"/>
      <Base:Potable value="false"/>
      <Base:DrinkMessageFirst/>
      <Base:DrinkMessageThird/>
      <Base:Transparency value="false"/>
      <Base:Unsafe value="false"/>
      <Base:Safe value="false"/>
      <Base:ClothesExpected value="false"/>
      <Base:DieMessageFirst/>
      <Base:DieMessageThird/>
    </Base:Misc>
    <Base:Details>
      <Base:Detail id="default" prime="true" def="false" abstract="false" hidden="false" luminosity="0" targetable_in_dark="false" plural="false">
        <Base:Preposition close="false" against="false" under="false" on="false" inside="false" near="false" over="false" behind="false" before="false" beside="false"/>
        <Base:Names>
          <Base:SNames>
            <Base:SName sname="text"/>
          </Base:SNames>
          <Base:PNames>
            <Base:PName pname="texts"/>
          </Base:PNames>
        </Base:Names>
        <Base:Adjectives/>
        <Base:Descriptions>
          <Base:Description type="brief">text</Base:Description>
        </Base:Descriptions>
        <Base:Exit door="false" closed="false" locked="false" never_obvious="false" obvious_when_open="false" hidden_when_closed="false" separate="false" self-locking="false" deadbolt="false"/>
        <Base:Climbable/>
      </Base:Detail>
    </Base:Details>
    <Base:Clothing>
      <Base:SingleWear value="false"/>
    </Base:Clothing>
    <Base:Crafting see_level="0" do_level="0" time="0" attention="false" held="false">
      <Base:Ingredients/>
      <Base:Tools/>
      <Base:CraftVerbs/>
    </Base:Crafting>
    <Base:InitialContents/>
    <Base:InitialProperties>
      <Base:InitialProperty property="trait:item:page04">
         "Generic:misc:bandage-sterile"
      </Base:InitialProperty>
      <Base:InitialProperty property="trait:page00">
         "THE MEDICAL ARTS: A Hand-Book for Healers"
      </Base:InitialProperty>
      <Base:InitialProperty property="trait:page01">
         "THE MEDICAL ARTS: A Hand-Book For Healers\<br/\>\<br/\>CONTENTS\<br/\>\<br/\>2. To the Reader\<br/\>3. On the Operation of the Body \<br/\>4. On Wounds and The Use Of Bandages\<br/\>5. Upon the Calling of Medicine\<br/\>6. The Novice\<br/\>7. The Junior Apprentice\<br/\>8. The Senior Apprentice\<br/\>9. The Fellowcraft\<br/\>10. The Journeyman\<br/\>11. The Artisan\<br/\>12. The Senior Artisan\<br/\>13. The Master\<br/\>14. The Master Adept\<br/\>15. The Grand Master\<br/\>16. Updates"
      </Base:InitialProperty>
      <Base:InitialProperty property="trait:page02">
         "TO THE READER\<br/\>\<br/\>Many ancient philosophers, when discussing the Nature of Man, observed That Man is naturally inclined to, and desirous of, Knowledge; and indeed it is palpable and apparent that Knowledge is the first Virtue a Child minds, as is apparent to them that do but with the eye of Reason heed their actions even whilst they are very young, even before they are a year old, even by natural Instinct. The wise man said, Knowledge is in Prosperity an Ornament, in Adversity a Refuge; and truly there is almost no greater enemy to Knowledge in the world than Pride and Covetousness. Some persons are so proud and envious withal, that they would have nobody know any thing but themselves; and others will let no thing go for less than Riches. The one I hope will shortly learn better manners, and the other be a burden too heavy for the Earth long to bear.\<br/\>The Subject which I here fixed my thoughts upon is not only the Description and Nature of Simples and Compounds, but all of Physick and Medicine too. There be little of disease among the folk of the Caistel Marrach, and much of that sorcerous in origin; but people usually boil Fennel with Fish, and know not why they do it but only for custom, when indeed the Original of it was founded upon Reason, because Fennel consumes that Phlegmatic quality of Fish, which is obnoxious to the Bodies of persons, Fennel being an Herb of Mercury, and he so great an Enemy to the Sign Pisces.\<br/\>My own body being sickly brought me easily into a capacity to know that Health was the greatest of all Blessings, and truly they were never sick that doth not believe it; then I considered that all Medicines were compounded of Herbs, Roots, Flowers, Seeds \&c. and this first set me awork in studying the Nature of Simples, most of which I knew by sight Before, and in writing my Breviary I drew out all the Virtues of vulgar Herbs, Plants, and Trees \&c. out of the best Authors I had or could get, and having done so, I set myself to study the Reason of them; I knew well enough the whole world and every thing in it was formed of a Composition of contrary Elements, and in such a harmony as must needs show the Grand Design of the World. I knew as well that the World though thus composed of contraries was one united Body, and humanity an Epitome of it, I knew those various affections in man in respect of Sickness and Health were caused Naturally by the various operations of the Macrocosm; and I could not be ignorant, that as the Cause is, so must the Cure be, and therefore he that would know the Reason of the operation of Herbs must look up as high as the Stars, and in the workings of Magic and Sorcery."
      </Base:InitialProperty>
      <Base:InitialProperty property="trait:page03">
         "ON THE OPERATION OF THE BODY\<br/\>\<br/\> The very Ground and Foundation of Physick is the great precept, that Nature heals all wounds, and provides a Medicine for all Disease, if we can but find it. All things in Nature and the World, including Disease, have rational Causes; these Causes are the fit subjects of study and debate. As the reason for each Cause is continually refined and the resulting Knowledge is written down, it follows that a physician now, if of studious nature, will know more than a physician of years past. Facts and experience are of little importance without proper Theory and Principles, becoming simple Superstition and folk ways. Theory and Dogma, on the other hand, become stale, and over reliant on old Authors, without a Reason besides fact that the writing is old and respected; and without even one wise Reason, young Novices in Physick are trained in the School of Tradition, and are taught just as a Parrot is taught to speak; an Author sayeth so, therefore ‘tis true, and if all Authors say be true, why do they contradict one another? Book learning is important but must not be accepted blindly; rather, Authors are authorities in as far as they are proved right through experience. Physick grows as an accumulative process through the study of books, the observation of facts, experience in treating patients, and the propounding of theories; the body of Medicine is appended or altered by each of its Members. \<br/\>The basic principle of life is the ‘pneuma’ or spirit, drawn from the general ‘world-spirit’ by the act of breathing. It enters the body via the trachea and lungs, where it passes through the arteria venalis (pulmonary veins) into the heart; there it is mixed with blood. Blood is constantly made in the liver from foodstuffs, and passes to the heart, where it acquires the ‘natural spirit’ (aka spiritus naturalis, or pneuma physicon) in the left ventricle, giving it the power of growth and nutrition; it then travels through the venous system to the tissues. Some of the blood passes across minute pores in the septum of the heart to get to the right ventricle, where it acquires another pneuma, the ‘vital spirit’ (aka spiritus vitalis, or pneuma zoticon), which travels out via the arterial system to give the body activity (and regulates body temperature). The blood which passes to the brain acquires the ‘animal spirit’ (aka spiritus animalis, or pneuma physicon), the noblest of the pneuma; this passes down the hollow nerves to initiate motion and sensation. \<br/\>The human microcosm consists of the four bodily humours: blood (also known as sanguine), phlegm, yellow bile (sometimes called choler), and black bile (or melancholer). Each of the four humours reflects the elements of the macrocosm: air, water, earth, and fire, respectively. The humours also have temperature and moisture properties: dry and moist, hot and cold, in various degrees. Blood is hot and wet, phlegm is cold and wet, black bile is cold and dry, and yellow bile is hot and dry. When a person became sick, one of the four humours is out of balance. To balance the humours, a physic will prescribe a Medicine, usually made from some combination of plants or animals. All plants and animals are categorized by their temperature and moisture. Thus, if a patient's illness is caused by an imbalance of phlegm, which is cold and wet, the physic might counteract that humour with its opposite, yellow bile; in which case, the physic would provide the patient with a prescription made from plants and animals that are hot and dry. Or, to restore the patient's physiological balance, a physic may prescribe leeches, or diuretic, laxative, emetic or sudorific medications, to reduce the imbalance. \<br/\>The humours have an effect upon the personality, which effect may vary with diet and disease. Each person has some innate imbalance or imperfection of humour, predisposing some temper or mood. Those who have a preponderance of blood are termed sanguinicus; of black bile, cholericus; of phlegm, flegmaticus; and of yellow bile, melancholicus. \<br/\>The signs of a disease or injury are a guide to the diagnosis and treatment of the patient; and useful medications produce a contrary effect to these signs. Thus a close, careful and perceptive observation of the signs is required. As the wise man said, Life is short, and the Art long; the occasion fleeting; experience fallacious, and judgment difficult. The Physician must not only be prepared to do what is right himself, but also to make the patient, the attendants, and externals cooperate."
      </Base:InitialProperty>
      <Base:InitialProperty property="trait:page04">
         "ON WOUNDS AND THE USE OF BANDAGES\<br/\>\<br/\>Cuts, stabs, and all such Wounds might be classified as either slight, serious and grave. If a patient with an unhealed grave wound should be wounded again, he or she will die. Patients must consent to the healing treatment. The initial treatment for a Wound consists of the application and dressing of a clean bandage – to which the patient must consent – followed by a longer healing period. The patient must not leave the presence of the healer until the treatment period is finished – a span of half an hour or so, depending on the skill of the healer – and must not remove the bandage until the healing period is complete – a span of up to ten days; else the beneficial effects of the treatment be lost. \<br/\>The chirurgeon must be holding a clean bandage when beginning treatment.\<br/\>Point to this page and a clean bandage will conveniently appear in your hand."
      </Base:InitialProperty>
      <Base:InitialProperty property="trait:page05">
         "UPON THE CALLING OF MEDICINE\<br/\>\<br/\>Ten levels of proficiency are commonly recognized for the art and craft of healing:\<br/\>\<br/\>1. Novice\<br/\>2. Junior Apprentice\<br/\>3. Senior Apprentice\<br/\>4. Fellowcraft\<br/\>5. Journeyman\<br/\>6. Artisan\<br/\>7. Senior Artisan\<br/\>8. Master\<br/\>9. Master Adept\<br/\>10. Grand Master"
      </Base:InitialProperty>
      <Base:InitialProperty property="trait:page06">
         "THE NOVICE\<br/\>\<br/\>Novices can only treat slight wounds; serious or grave wounds are beyond their skill. Treatment = 30 minutes. Slight = 10 days."
      </Base:InitialProperty>
      <Base:InitialProperty property="trait:page07">
         "THE JUNIOR APPRENTICE\<br/\>\<br/\>Junior apprentices can treat slight and serious wounds, but not grave wounds. Treatment = 27 minutes. Slight = 9 days. Serious = 18 days. To become a Junior Apprentice, one must have gained the skill of a novice and proved oneself worthy of serious study; and swear the Deontological Oath as follows: \<br/\>\<br/\> I swear by all the gods and goddesses, making them my witnesses, that I will fulfill according to my ability and judgment this oath and this covenant: To hold whomsoever has taught me this art as my master; and by precept, lecture and every other mode of instruction I will impart a knowledge of the Art to pupils who have signed this covenant and have taken an oath according to the medical law, but to no one else; and to be just and generous to my fellow practitioners. I will follow that system of regimen which, according to my ability and judgment, I consider for the benefit of my patients; I will keep them from harm and injustice. I will exercise my art solely for the cure of my patients; I will neither give a deadly drug to anybody if asked for it, nor perform no criminal operation, nor will I suggest any such counsel. I will lead my life and practice my art in uprightness and honor. Whatever houses I may visit, I will come for the benefit of the sick, abstaining from all intentional injustice and all mischief and in particular abstaining from the seduction of both female and male persons. What I may see or hear of the lives of persons which is not fitting to be spoken, whether in connection with my practice or not, I will keep inviolably secret. If I fulfill this oath and do not violate it, may it be granted to me to enjoy life and art, being honored with fame among all men for all time to come; if I transgress it and swear falsely, may the opposite be my lot."
      </Base:InitialProperty>
      <Base:InitialProperty property="trait:page08">
         "THE SENIOR APPRENTICE\<br/\>\<br/\>Senior apprentices can treat slight and serious wounds, but not grave wounds. Treatment = 24 minutes. Slight = 8 days. Serious = 16 days."
      </Base:InitialProperty>
      <Base:InitialProperty property="trait:page09">
         "THE FELLOWCRAFT\<br/\>\<br/\>Fellowcraft healers can treat all wounds. Treatment = 21 minutes. Slight = 7 days. Serious = 14 days. Grave = 21 days."
      </Base:InitialProperty>
      <Base:InitialProperty property="trait:page10">
         "THE JOURNEYMAN\<br/\>\<br/\>Journeymen can treat all wounds, and begin the compilation of a personal breviary, or leech-book, describing diseases, their symptoms, diagnosis, and treatment. Treatment = 18 minutes. Slight = 6 days. Serious = 12 days. Grave = 18 days."
      </Base:InitialProperty>
      <Base:InitialProperty property="trait:page11">
         "THE ARTISAN\<br/\>\<br/\>Artisans can treat all wounds. Treatment = 15 minutes. Slight = 5 days. Serious = 10 days. Grave = 15 days."
      </Base:InitialProperty>
      <Base:InitialProperty property="trait:page12">
         "THE SENIOR ARTISAN\<br/\>\<br/\>Senior Artisans can treat all wounds. Treatment = 12 minutes. Slight = 4 days. Serious = 8 days. Grave = 12 days."
      </Base:InitialProperty>
      <Base:InitialProperty property="trait:page13">
         "THE MASTER\<br/\>\<br/\>Masters can treat all wounds. This is the minimum level of skill for the Queen’s court to extend the title of ‘Doctor’ to a healer. Treatment = 9 minutes. Slight = 3 days. Serious = 6 days. Grave = 9 days."
      </Base:InitialProperty>
      <Base:InitialProperty property="trait:page14">
         "THE MASTER ADEPT\<br/\>\<br/\>Master Adepts can treat all wounds. Treatment = 6 minutes. Slight = 2 days. Serious = 4 days. Grave = 6 days."
      </Base:InitialProperty>
      <Base:InitialProperty property="trait:page15">
         "THE GRAND MASTER\<br/\>\<br/\>The Grand Master can treat all wounds. Treatment Period = 3 minutes. Slight = 1 day. Serious = 2 days. Grave = 3 days."
      </Base:InitialProperty>
      <Base:InitialProperty property="trait:page16">
         "UPDATES\<br/\>\<br/\> The text of this book will mysteriously update itself as more information becomes available.\<br/\>\<br/\>Please bring typographical errors or other textual problems found in this volume to the attention of any StoryHost."
      </Base:InitialProperty>
    </Base:InitialProperties>
    <Core:Properties>
      <Core:Property property="skill:fatigue">1.0</Core:Property>
      <Core:Property property="trait:item:page04">
         "Generic:misc:bandage-sterile"
      </Core:Property>
      <Core:Property property="trait:page00">
         "THE MEDICAL ARTS: A Hand-Book for Healers"
      </Core:Property>
      <Core:Property property="trait:page01">
         "THE MEDICAL ARTS: A Hand-Book For Healers\<br/\>\<br/\>CONTENTS\<br/\>\<br/\>2. To the Reader\<br/\>3. On the Operation of the Body \<br/\>4. On Wounds and The Use Of Bandages\<br/\>5. Upon the Calling of Medicine\<br/\>6. The Novice\<br/\>7. The Junior Apprentice\<br/\>8. The Senior Apprentice\<br/\>9. The Fellowcraft\<br/\>10. The Journeyman\<br/\>11. The Artisan\<br/\>12. The Senior Artisan\<br/\>13. The Master\<br/\>14. The Master Adept\<br/\>15. The Grand Master\<br/\>16. Updates"
      </Core:Property>
      <Core:Property property="trait:page02">
         "TO THE READER\<br/\>\<br/\>Many ancient philosophers, when discussing the Nature of Man, observed That Man is naturally inclined to, and desirous of, Knowledge; and indeed it is palpable and apparent that Knowledge is the first Virtue a Child minds, as is apparent to them that do but with the eye of Reason heed their actions even whilst they are very young, even before they are a year old, even by natural Instinct. The wise man said, Knowledge is in Prosperity an Ornament, in Adversity a Refuge; and truly there is almost no greater enemy to Knowledge in the world than Pride and Covetousness. Some persons are so proud and envious withal, that they would have nobody know any thing but themselves; and others will let no thing go for less than Riches. The one I hope will shortly learn better manners, and the other be a burden too heavy for the Earth long to bear.\<br/\>The Subject which I here fixed my thoughts upon is not only the Description and Nature of Simples and Compounds, but all of Physick and Medicine too. There be little of disease among the folk of the Caistel Marrach, and much of that sorcerous in origin; but people usually boil Fennel with Fish, and know not why they do it but only for custom, when indeed the Original of it was founded upon Reason, because Fennel consumes that Phlegmatic quality of Fish, which is obnoxious to the Bodies of persons, Fennel being an Herb of Mercury, and he so great an Enemy to the Sign Pisces.\<br/\>My own body being sickly brought me easily into a capacity to know that Health was the greatest of all Blessings, and truly they were never sick that doth not believe it; then I considered that all Medicines were compounded of Herbs, Roots, Flowers, Seeds \&c. and this first set me awork in studying the Nature of Simples, most of which I knew by sight Before, and in writing my Breviary I drew out all the Virtues of vulgar Herbs, Plants, and Trees \&c. out of the best Authors I had or could get, and having done so, I set myself to study the Reason of them; I knew well enough the whole world and every thing in it was formed of a Composition of contrary Elements, and in such a harmony as must needs show the Grand Design of the World. I knew as well that the World though thus composed of contraries was one united Body, and humanity an Epitome of it, I knew those various affections in man in respect of Sickness and Health were caused Naturally by the various operations of the Macrocosm; and I could not be ignorant, that as the Cause is, so must the Cure be, and therefore he that would know the Reason of the operation of Herbs must look up as high as the Stars, and in the workings of Magic and Sorcery."
      </Core:Property>
      <Core:Property property="trait:page03">
         "ON THE OPERATION OF THE BODY\<br/\>\<br/\> The very Ground and Foundation of Physick is the great precept, that Nature heals all wounds, and provides a Medicine for all Disease, if we can but find it. All things in Nature and the World, including Disease, have rational Causes; these Causes are the fit subjects of study and debate. As the reason for each Cause is continually refined and the resulting Knowledge is written down, it follows that a physician now, if of studious nature, will know more than a physician of years past. Facts and experience are of little importance without proper Theory and Principles, becoming simple Superstition and folk ways. Theory and Dogma, on the other hand, become stale, and over reliant on old Authors, without a Reason besides fact that the writing is old and respected; and without even one wise Reason, young Novices in Physick are trained in the School of Tradition, and are taught just as a Parrot is taught to speak; an Author sayeth so, therefore ‘tis true, and if all Authors say be true, why do they contradict one another? Book learning is important but must not be accepted blindly; rather, Authors are authorities in as far as they are proved right through experience. Physick grows as an accumulative process through the study of books, the observation of facts, experience in treating patients, and the propounding of theories; the body of Medicine is appended or altered by each of its Members. \<br/\>The basic principle of life is the ‘pneuma’ or spirit, drawn from the general ‘world-spirit’ by the act of breathing. It enters the body via the trachea and lungs, where it passes through the arteria venalis (pulmonary veins) into the heart; there it is mixed with blood. Blood is constantly made in the liver from foodstuffs, and passes to the heart, where it acquires the ‘natural spirit’ (aka spiritus naturalis, or pneuma physicon) in the left ventricle, giving it the power of growth and nutrition; it then travels through the venous system to the tissues. Some of the blood passes across minute pores in the septum of the heart to get to the right ventricle, where it acquires another pneuma, the ‘vital spirit’ (aka spiritus vitalis, or pneuma zoticon), which travels out via the arterial system to give the body activity (and regulates body temperature). The blood which passes to the brain acquires the ‘animal spirit’ (aka spiritus animalis, or pneuma physicon), the noblest of the pneuma; this passes down the hollow nerves to initiate motion and sensation. \<br/\>The human microcosm consists of the four bodily humours: blood (also known as sanguine), phlegm, yellow bile (sometimes called choler), and black bile (or melancholer). Each of the four humours reflects the elements of the macrocosm: air, water, earth, and fire, respectively. The humours also have temperature and moisture properties: dry and moist, hot and cold, in various degrees. Blood is hot and wet, phlegm is cold and wet, black bile is cold and dry, and yellow bile is hot and dry. When a person became sick, one of the four humours is out of balance. To balance the humours, a physic will prescribe a Medicine, usually made from some combination of plants or animals. All plants and animals are categorized by their temperature and moisture. Thus, if a patient's illness is caused by an imbalance of phlegm, which is cold and wet, the physic might counteract that humour with its opposite, yellow bile; in which case, the physic would provide the patient with a prescription made from plants and animals that are hot and dry. Or, to restore the patient's physiological balance, a physic may prescribe leeches, or diuretic, laxative, emetic or sudorific medications, to reduce the imbalance. \<br/\>The humours have an effect upon the personality, which effect may vary with diet and disease. Each person has some innate imbalance or imperfection of humour, predisposing some temper or mood. Those who have a preponderance of blood are termed sanguinicus; of black bile, cholericus; of phlegm, flegmaticus; and of yellow bile, melancholicus. \<br/\>The signs of a disease or injury are a guide to the diagnosis and treatment of the patient; and useful medications produce a contrary effect to these signs. Thus a close, careful and perceptive observation of the signs is required. As the wise man said, Life is short, and the Art long; the occasion fleeting; experience fallacious, and judgment difficult. The Physician must not only be prepared to do what is right himself, but also to make the patient, the attendants, and externals cooperate."
      </Core:Property>
      <Core:Property property="trait:page04">
         "ON WOUNDS AND THE USE OF BANDAGES\<br/\>\<br/\>Cuts, stabs, and all such Wounds might be classified as either slight, serious and grave. If a patient with an unhealed grave wound should be wounded again, he or she will die. Patients must consent to the healing treatment. The initial treatment for a Wound consists of the application and dressing of a clean bandage – to which the patient must consent – followed by a longer healing period. The patient must not leave the presence of the healer until the treatment period is finished – a span of half an hour or so, depending on the skill of the healer – and must not remove the bandage until the healing period is complete – a span of up to ten days; else the beneficial effects of the treatment be lost. \<br/\>The chirurgeon must be holding a clean bandage when beginning treatment.\<br/\>Point to this page and a clean bandage will conveniently appear in your hand."
      </Core:Property>
      <Core:Property property="trait:page05">
         "UPON THE CALLING OF MEDICINE\<br/\>\<br/\>Ten levels of proficiency are commonly recognized for the art and craft of healing:\<br/\>\<br/\>1. Novice\<br/\>2. Junior Apprentice\<br/\>3. Senior Apprentice\<br/\>4. Fellowcraft\<br/\>5. Journeyman\<br/\>6. Artisan\<br/\>7. Senior Artisan\<br/\>8. Master\<br/\>9. Master Adept\<br/\>10. Grand Master"
      </Core:Property>
      <Core:Property property="trait:page06">
         "THE NOVICE\<br/\>\<br/\>Novices can only treat slight wounds; serious or grave wounds are beyond their skill. Treatment = 30 minutes. Slight = 10 days."
      </Core:Property>
      <Core:Property property="trait:page07">
         "THE JUNIOR APPRENTICE\<br/\>\<br/\>Junior apprentices can treat slight and serious wounds, but not grave wounds. Treatment = 27 minutes. Slight = 9 days. Serious = 18 days. To become a Junior Apprentice, one must have gained the skill of a novice and proved oneself worthy of serious study; and swear the Deontological Oath as follows: \<br/\>\<br/\> I swear by all the gods and goddesses, making them my witnesses, that I will fulfill according to my ability and judgment this oath and this covenant: To hold whomsoever has taught me this art as my master; and by precept, lecture and every other mode of instruction I will impart a knowledge of the Art to pupils who have signed this covenant and have taken an oath according to the medical law, but to no one else; and to be just and generous to my fellow practitioners. I will follow that system of regimen which, according to my ability and judgment, I consider for the benefit of my patients; I will keep them from harm and injustice. I will exercise my art solely for the cure of my patients; I will neither give a deadly drug to anybody if asked for it, nor perform no criminal operation, nor will I suggest any such counsel. I will lead my life and practice my art in uprightness and honor. Whatever houses I may visit, I will come for the benefit of the sick, abstaining from all intentional injustice and all mischief and in particular abstaining from the seduction of both female and male persons. What I may see or hear of the lives of persons which is not fitting to be spoken, whether in connection with my practice or not, I will keep inviolably secret. If I fulfill this oath and do not violate it, may it be granted to me to enjoy life and art, being honored with fame among all men for all time to come; if I transgress it and swear falsely, may the opposite be my lot."
      </Core:Property>
      <Core:Property property="trait:page08">
         "THE SENIOR APPRENTICE\<br/\>\<br/\>Senior apprentices can treat slight and serious wounds, but not grave wounds. Treatment = 24 minutes. Slight = 8 days. Serious = 16 days."
      </Core:Property>
      <Core:Property property="trait:page09">
         "THE FELLOWCRAFT\<br/\>\<br/\>Fellowcraft healers can treat all wounds. Treatment = 21 minutes. Slight = 7 days. Serious = 14 days. Grave = 21 days."
      </Core:Property>
      <Core:Property property="trait:page10">
         "THE JOURNEYMAN\<br/\>\<br/\>Journeymen can treat all wounds, and begin the compilation of a personal breviary, or leech-book, describing diseases, their symptoms, diagnosis, and treatment. Treatment = 18 minutes. Slight = 6 days. Serious = 12 days. Grave = 18 days."
      </Core:Property>
      <Core:Property property="trait:page11">
         "THE ARTISAN\<br/\>\<br/\>Artisans can treat all wounds. Treatment = 15 minutes. Slight = 5 days. Serious = 10 days. Grave = 15 days."
      </Core:Property>
      <Core:Property property="trait:page12">
         "THE SENIOR ARTISAN\<br/\>\<br/\>Senior Artisans can treat all wounds. Treatment = 12 minutes. Slight = 4 days. Serious = 8 days. Grave = 12 days."
      </Core:Property>
      <Core:Property property="trait:page13">
         "THE MASTER\<br/\>\<br/\>Masters can treat all wounds. This is the minimum level of skill for the Queen’s court to extend the title of ‘Doctor’ to a healer. Treatment = 9 minutes. Slight = 3 days. Serious = 6 days. Grave = 9 days."
      </Core:Property>
      <Core:Property property="trait:page14">
         "THE MASTER ADEPT\<br/\>\<br/\>Master Adepts can treat all wounds. Treatment = 6 minutes. Slight = 2 days. Serious = 4 days. Grave = 6 days."
      </Core:Property>
      <Core:Property property="trait:page15">
         "THE GRAND MASTER\<br/\>\<br/\>The Grand Master can treat all wounds. Treatment Period = 3 minutes. Slight = 1 day. Serious = 2 days. Grave = 3 days."
      </Core:Property>
      <Core:Property property="trait:page16">
         "UPDATES\<br/\>\<br/\> The text of this book will mysteriously update itself as more information becomes available.\<br/\>\<br/\>Please bring typographical errors or other textual problems found in this volume to the attention of any StoryHost."
      </Core:Property>
      <Core:Property property="volition">0</Core:Property>
    </Core:Properties>
    <Notes:Notes>
      <Notes:Category cat="QA" catstate="Open">
        <Notes:Note ix="971734080" state="Comment" user="brianm">
           Text and item list for the Healers Book.
        </Notes:Note>
      </Notes:Category>
    </Notes:Notes>
  </Base:Thing>
</object>
