<object clone="/base/obj/thing" owner="SID">
  <Base:Thing>
    <Ur:UrObject/>
    <Base:Bulk immobile="false" mass="0.3" density="1.1"/>
    <Base:Container flexible="false" transparent-container="false" public-container="false" tight="false" capacity="0" maxweight="0"/>
    <Base:Misc gender="neuter" volition="false" weapon="false" default_stance="none" combinable="false" discrete="false" by_weight="false" tight="false" scriptrunner="false">
      <Base:Edible value="false"/>
      <Base:Potable value="false"/>
      <Base:DrinkMessageFirst/>
      <Base:DrinkMessageThird/>
      <Base:Transparency value="false"/>
      <Base:Unsafe value="false"/>
      <Base:Safe value="false"/>
      <Base:ClothesExpected value="false"/>
      <Base:DieMessageFirst/>
      <Base:DieMessageThird/>
    </Base:Misc>
    <Base:Details>
      <Base:Detail id="default" prime="true" def="false" abstract="false" hidden="false" luminosity="0" targetable_in_dark="false" plural="false">
        <Base:Preposition close="false" against="false" under="false" on="false" inside="false" near="false" over="false" behind="false" before="false" beside="false"/>
        <Base:Names>
          <Base:SNames>
            <Base:SName sname="text"/>
          </Base:SNames>
          <Base:PNames>
            <Base:PName pname="texts"/>
          </Base:PNames>
        </Base:Names>
        <Base:Adjectives/>
        <Base:Descriptions>
          <Base:Description type="brief">text</Base:Description>
        </Base:Descriptions>
        <Base:Exit door="false" closed="false" locked="false" never_obvious="false" obvious_when_open="false" hidden_when_closed="false" separate="false" self-locking="false" deadbolt="false"/>
        <Base:Climbable/>
      </Base:Detail>
    </Base:Details>
    <Base:Clothing>
      <Base:SingleWear value="false"/>
    </Base:Clothing>
    <Base:Crafting see_level="0" do_level="0" time="0" attention="false" held="false">
      <Base:Ingredients/>
      <Base:Tools/>
      <Base:CraftVerbs/>
    </Base:Crafting>
    <Base:InitialContents/>
    <Base:InitialProperties>
      <Base:InitialProperty property="trait:page00">
         "ART OF THE BLADE\<br/\>\<br/\>"
      </Base:InitialProperty>
      <Base:InitialProperty property="trait:page01">
         "ART OF THE BLADE\<br/\>\<br/\>By ser Daris\<br/\>\<br/\>I base my system partly on the instruction I received long ago from Lord Bernier, and partly on certain lucid works treating on combat and swordplay. To the authors of those works, to Lord Bernier, and to my many opponents since then, I give thanks for both skill and insight."
      </Base:InitialProperty>
      <Base:InitialProperty property="trait:page02">
         "THE SWORD\<br/\>\<br/\>The sword consists of two principal parts – the blade and the hilt.\<br/\>\<br/\>The Hilt: The hilt of a sword consists, for simplicity, of everything not part of the blade forward of the guard. A hilt usually consists of a guard, a grip, and a pommel.\<br/\>\<br/\>The Grip: The handle by which the weapon is held, with the strong hand. Usually the grip is made of wood, bone, metal or ivory with leather, wire or cord wrapped around it; it is built around the tang, a continuation of the blade itself. Wood and horn are preferred for the body of the grip, as they absorb some of the shock of combat.\<br/\>\<br/\>The Pommel: At the extreme end of the sword is the pommel. This item, typically a finial, disk or knob of steel, is of sufficient size and weight to balance the sword; the tang is welded, bolted or otherwise securely fasted to it. It also has minor functions: to protect the smaller fingers, to secure the fingers on the grip, and to provide a striking surface for some of the more rowdy bludgeoning blows. \<br/\>\<br/\>The Guard: This portion of the weapon takes many forms, from a brief disc barely larger than the blade itself, to complicated structures or shells surrounding the hand and connecting to the pommel. These structures have their root at the joint between the grip and the blade. The guard is often the most easily discerned difference between various types of swords. The weapon used for military purposes within the castle has a cross-bar blade, also known as a quillon; with sometimes a few smaller curled bars to protect the grip."
      </Base:InitialProperty>
      <Base:InitialProperty property="trait:page03">
         "The Blade: The blade carries the cutting edge or edges (if any) of the sword and serves to move the point to hit the opponent. The blade as a worked object is divided into three parts: the tang, which fits within the hilt; the forte, the half of the visible blade closest to the guard, and the strongest point of the blade; and the foible, the remaining half of the visible blade at the outer end, and the weakest section. The edges of older swords will be parallel; our more modern weapons taper slightly from the ricasso to the point. Some swords are sharpened completely, partially or not at all on one or both edges; for a practice sword the edges of the blade are neither tapered nor sharpened. Blades may bear one or more fullers (grooves) on each face, or they may have ridges. At the base of the blade, where it meets the hilt, there is usually a short section with an unsharpened – in fact, square – edge: the ricasso. The maker’s mark is usually inscribed or engraved here.\<br/\>\<br/\>The Point: This is of course located at the far end of the blade, on the foible. In a practice or rebated sword the blade is blunted or bent back at the very end, or carries a knob."
      </Base:InitialProperty>
      <Base:InitialProperty property="trait:page04">
         "Guard [command: guard]\<br/\>\<br/\> A proper guard position is the root of all proper swordplay. Care must be taken not to confuse the term with ‘parry’, a distinct defensive motion for the purpose of stopping a cut or thrust. The guard position defends your strong side from attack and provides the readiest place for a switch to any other defensive position or to an attack. \<br/\>\<br/\>To take the guard position begin with the feet lined up, about shoulder-length apart with front foot pointing towards the opponent and the rear foot perpendicular to the front foot. Bend at the knees, in a half-crouch. The torso should remain straight; you should not lean forward, back or to either side. Bend the weapon arm at the elbow. The distance between the elbow and your body should be one hand length. The traditional “on guard” calls for the blade to be in position for the sixte parry. Your strong arm should be positioned so that your blade will block an attack to your weapon side from hitting your body. Put your weak hand at your hip, or behind your back, or behind the head; unless you are armored, or equipped with, and skilled with, some defensive weapon such as a shield, cloak or dagger. A common flaw of a poor swordsman, experienced or otherwise, is a poorly-learned guard position.\<br/\>\<br/\>Holding the Sword\<br/\>\<br/\>The sword is held lightly but firmly with the thumb along the back of the grip, and the fingers closed round it so that the center knuckles are in line with the edge of the blade. At times the thumb may be shifted to encircle the grip, similarly to the fingers, to relieve the hand."
      </Base:InitialProperty>
      <Base:InitialProperty property="trait:page05">
         "Defense [command: recover]\<br/\>\<br/\>The parry is a movement of the blade that prevents the opponent's blade from hitting your target.\<br/\>\<br/\> You can be attacked in three basic areas: your guard side, your flank side or your head. Accordingly, there are three main parries used in sword, one for each attack you need to defend against. The guard parry (known as the sixte) has your arm in the guard position with the knuckles facing outward and the blade angled at 45 degrees from your hand. The blade should be in position to block an incoming blow from that angle. When you are in guard this is the parry you should use. The flank parry is made by beginning with a guard parry and bending your hand at the wrist and your arm at the elbow. Your arm should be across your body. Make the head parry by raising your weapon hand bent at the elbow with the blade almost horizontal right above your head about a foot in front of your face. Check all your parries by making sure an attack to that side cannot land. \<br/\>\<br/\>[note that the recover command is automatically part of the attacks, and thus the command is not often employed in actual play; however, training in this important skill will improve a swordsman’s defense ability.]"
      </Base:InitialProperty>
      <Base:InitialProperty property="trait:page06">
         "The Dodge [command: dodge]\<br/\>\<br/\>Swordsmen in desperate straits may wish to employ any of the variety of dodges and tricks which are known of. Of course, one can only rarely attack while engaged in a dodge; but sometimes this tactic is called for."
      </Base:InitialProperty>
      <Base:InitialProperty property="trait:page07">
         "The Rest [command: rest]\<br/\>\<br/\>In duels of some duration, or when the opponent is out of reach, the resting guard may prove useful when recovering one’s stamina. Lower the sword hand until the pommel rests on the thigh about six or eight inches above the knee.\<br/\>\<br/\>[note also the command: health]"
      </Base:InitialProperty>
      <Base:InitialProperty property="trait:page08">
         "Advance \& Retire [commands: advance, retire]\<br/\>\<br/\>If guard is the root of swordplay, the advance and the retire are the main branches of movement. A well executed advance will press your attack against your opponent and force them to react rather then lead, and the best defense against this is a careful retreat. \<br/\>\<br/\>To execute an advance, begin by keeping your body in on guard position. Lift the front foot, toe first, then heel, and put it down one step forward, heel first and then toe. Your upper body should remain still. Next, you should pick up your back foot and place it so that you are again in on guard position. Bring your upper torso forward with your back foot. \<br/\>\<br/\>Retire is essentially like the advance in reverse. Move your feet like in the advance except in the reverse direction and order. Begin by moving your back foot backwards, and then bring back your torso and front foot (toes picked up first, heel put down first. One must conduct a proper retire in order to gain the distance for conducting some maneuvers, such as the lunge.\<br/\>\<br/\>In both the advance and retire, it is important to keep the upper torso perfectly straight. Also make sure that your heels remain lined up and your feet perpendicular. Many beginners have a tendency to let their feet drift out of line, watch this carefully. \<br/\>\<br/\>To practice the advance and retire, go to a place where there is a straight line on the ground, which you can follow. Advance or retreat along that line over and over again. You should get to the point where you don't need to look at the line to keep going straight."
      </Base:InitialProperty>
      <Base:InitialProperty property="trait:page09">
         "The Thrust [command: thrust, jab]\<br/\>\<br/\> The thrust is the quickest way to get close to your opponent and allows you to move into a defensive position quickly if your attack does not land. For the skilled swordsman, the thrust is the best form of attack, speedy and safe. \<br/\>\<br/\>To thrust, begin in an on guard position. There are two parts to the thrust: the attack and the recovery. The attack delivers the blade to your opponent, and the recovery will bring you back to the guard position. To begin the attack, extend your arm forward pointing towards the center of your opponent's chest. Finish by throwing out your front leg forward so that your knee is at a right angle and when you look down, your leg eclipses your foot. Your back foot should remain firmly planted. Many swordsmen prefer to throw their weak arm out behind them to help channel their momentum into the lunge; this is a matter of preference. \<br/\>\<br/\>The recovery is the simple act of returning to on guard position. Pull back your leg, bringing your torso back, but leave your arm extended. It will make it easier for you to move to a parry (described below). This whole lunge, the attack and the recovery, should be one continuous, swift movement. If there is a pause or a break between movements you will open yourself to attack."
      </Base:InitialProperty>
      <Base:InitialProperty property="trait:page10">
         "The Slash [command: slash, cut]\<br/\>\<br/\> The slash, an attack performed with the edge of the blade, is not so quickly performed as the thrust; nor is it as safe for the swordsman. However, for a swordsman of superior strength, or a desperate one, this attack may prove useful, as it may can quickly overcome an opponent. \<br/\>\<br/\>To slash, begin in an on guard position. Slashes may be made vertically, horizontally upwards or downwards, or horizontally. The common slash, downward horizontally from your strong side, is made as follows: extend the sword arm somewhat, the hand to be in quarte, and the point a little raised, the hilt of the sword being about the height of the chin, and the edge directed obliquely downwards towards your weak side. Then, drop the point diagonally downwards from your strong side to your weak side, taking care that the edge leads during the passage of the blade along the line on the target; then allow the wrist to revolve so as to bring the thumb downwards, and the back of the hand and the flat of the blade opposite your weak side, and cause the sword to describe a complete circle, thus bringing it again to the position of guard. These movements are carried out continuously, and when done well is a useful tool of the swordsman."
      </Base:InitialProperty>
      <Base:InitialProperty property="trait:page11">
         "Advanced Attacks: The Feint [command: feint]\<br/\>\<br/\> Many times a thrust or lunge attack will not be enough to strike your opponent. They only have to move their blade a short distance to execute a parry while the point of your sword needs to travel a much greater distance before that parry can be made. Because of this compound attacks were created. These are attacks of at least two parts that make it harder for your opponent to parry. The most common compound attack is the feint attack. To perform a feint, extend your point towards one side of your opponent, and then switch your line to the other side in the middle of the lunge. If your feint was convincing, then your opponent will try to parry it as if it were an attack. When you attack to their other side, they will have to work harder to parry it. You can feint many times with one action. You perform an attack, starting with your blade towards one line on the advance, then another at the beginning of the thrust and finishing with a different line. If you can do it well, the opponent will have no idea where to parry."
      </Base:InitialProperty>
      <Base:InitialProperty property="trait:page12">
         "Advanced Attacks: The Lunge [command: lunge]\<br/\>\<br/\>The lunge is a combination move beginning with an advance and ending with a thrust as the attack; two of the most basic moves in swordplay. But the advance lunge itself is so much more than basic; it is a distance gaining move and powerful attack, and a strategy to get the advantage of an opponent. It can lend great power to quick movement. Many complex bladework moves can be executed during the advancing lunge such as the pris de fer (taking of the iron), a move that shows total control of the situation and beautiful finesse of movement. In short, the advance lunge can stand for everything that is beautiful about the art of the sword. \<br/\>\<br/\>To conduct a lunge, one must first gain the proper distance from one’s opponent; the opponent might first retreat, or the swordsman may retire to the correct measure."
      </Base:InitialProperty>
      <Base:InitialProperty property="trait:page13">
         "Advanced Attacks: The Slip [command: slip]\<br/\>\<br/\>The slip is a very sophisticated combination attack, in which the swordsman dodges aside, defending against the opponent's blade, and makes a thrust. The slip is somewhat slow to recover from -- a period of great danger. Few novices at swordplay can succeed in a slip; but for the skilled, it is a powerful tool."
      </Base:InitialProperty>
      <Base:InitialProperty property="trait:page14">
         "Advance: a movement forward by step, cross, or balestra. \<br/\>Attack: the initial offensive action made by extending the sword arm and continuously threatening the opponent. \<br/\>Attack au Fer: an attack that is prepared by deflecting the opponent's blade, e.g. beat, froissement, pressure. \<br/\>Balestra: a forward hop or jump, typically followed by an attack such as a lunge or fleche. \<br/\>Beat: an attempt to knock the opponent's blade aside or out of line by using one's foible against the opponent's foible. \<br/\>Bind: an action in which the opponent's blade is forced into the diagonally opposite line. \<br/\>Bout: swordplay practice at which the score is kept; or, a single conversation without a wound being inflicted. \<br/\>Broadsword: an older military sword; any straight-bladed, double-edged, single-handed cutting sword. \<br/\>Broken Time: a sudden change in the tempo of one swordsman's actions, used to fool the opponent into responding at the wrong time. \<br/\>Button: the blunted tip on the end of some practice swords. \<br/\>Change of Engagement: engagement of the opponent's blade in the opposite line. \<br/\>Compound: also composed; an attack or riposte incorporating one or more feints to the opposite line that the action finishes in. \<br/\>Conversation: the back-and-forth play of the blades in a bout, composed of phrases punctuated by gaps of no blade action. \<br/\>Counter-attack: an attack made against the right-of-way, or in response to the opponent's attack. \<br/\>Counter-disengage: a disengage in the opposite direction, to deceive the counter-parry. \<br/\>Counter-parry: a parry made in the opposite line to the attack; i.e. the defender first comes around to the opposite side of the opponent's blade. \<br/\>Counter-riposte: an attack that follows a parry of the opponent's riposte. \<br/\>Counter-time: an attack that responds to the opponent's counter-attack, typically a riposte following the parry of the counter-attack. \<br/\>Coupe': also cut-over; an attack or deception that passes around the opponent's tip. \<br/\>Croise: also semi-bind; an action in which the opponent's blade is forced into the high or low line on the same side. \<br/\>Cross: an advance or retreat by crossing one leg over the other; also either a forward cross or backwards cross. \<br/\>Cut: an attack made with a chopping motion of the blade, landing with the edge or point. \<br/\>Deception: avoidance of an attempt to engage the blades; see disengage, coupe' \<br/\>Derobement: deception of the attack au fer or prise de fer. \<br/\>Direct: an attack or riposte that finishes in the same line in which it was formed, with no feints out of that line. \<br/\>Disengage: a circular movement of the blade that deceives the opponent's parry, removes the blades from engagement, or changes the line of engagement. \<br/\>Displacement: moving the target to avoid an attack; dodging. \<br/\>Double': an attack or riposte that describes a complete circle around the opponent's blade, and finishes in the opposite line. \<br/\>Dry: a bout with practice weapons, as opposed to wet, a bout or duel of where there is risk of blood. \<br/\>Engagement: when the blades are in contact with each other, e.g. during a parry, attack au fer, prise de fer, or graze. \<br/\>En Garde: also on guard; the basic position; the stance that swordsmen assume when preparing to engage; the guard position subsequent to the salute. \<br/\>Envelopment: an engagement that sweeps the opponent's blade through a full circle. \<br/\>False: an action that is intended to fail, but draw a predicted reaction from the opponent; also, the back edge of a blade with only one sharp edge. \<br/\>Feint: attacking into one line with the intention of switching to another line before the attack is completed. \<br/\>Finta in tempo: lit. \\"feint in time\\"; a feint of counter-attack that draws a counter-time parry, which is deceived. \<br/\>Fleche: lit. \\"arrow\\"; an attack in which the aggressor leaps off his leading foot, attempts to make the hit, and then passes the opponent at a run."
      </Base:InitialProperty>
      <Base:InitialProperty property="trait:page15">
         "Flying Parry or Riposte: a parry with a backwards glide and riposte by cut-over. \<br/\>Foible: the upper, weaker part of the blade. \<br/\>Forte: the lower, strong part of the blade. \<br/\>Froissement: an attack that displaces the opponent's blade by a strong grazing action. \<br/\>Graze: also glissade; an attack or feint that slides along the opponent's blade. \<br/\>Guard: the metal cup, ba, bars or bow that protects the hand from being hit. Also, the defensive position assumed when not attacking. \<br/\>Hilt: the handle of a sword, consisting of guard, grip, and pommel. \<br/\>In Quartata: an attack made with a quarter turn to the inside, concealing the front but exposing the back. \<br/\>In Time: when a stop-hit arrives at least one ‘time’ before the original attack. \<br/\>Indirect: an attack or riposte that finishes in the opposite line to which it was formed, by means of a disengage or coupe'. \<br/\>Insistence: forcing an attack through the parry. \<br/\>Interception: a counter-attack that intercepts and checks an indirect attack or other disengagement. \<br/\>Invitation: a line that is intentionally left open to encourage the opponent to attack. \<br/\>Line: the main direction of an attack (e.g., high/low, inside/outside), often equated to the parry that must be made to deflect the attack; also point in line. \<br/\>Longsword: the ordinary military and duelling weapon of the castle, with a tapering double-edged blade useable for both cut and thrust work; normally having a simple crossbar guard. \<br/\>Lunge: a thrusting attack made by extending the rear leg and landing on the bent front leg. \<br/\>Mal-parry: a parry that fails to prevent the attack from landing. \<br/\>Measure: the distance between opponents. \<br/\>Neuvieme: an unconventional parry sometimes described as ‘blade behind the back’, pointing down (a variant of octave), other times similar to elevated sixte. \<br/\>Octave: parry with the blade down and to the outside, wrist supinated. \<br/\>Opposition: holding the opponent's blade in a non-threatening line; a time-hit; any attack or counter-attack with opposition. \<br/\>Parry: a block of the attack, made with the forte of one's own blade. \<br/\>Pass: an attack made with a cross; e.g. fleche. Also, the act of moving past the opponent. \<br/\>Passata-sotto: a lunge made by dropping one hand to the floor. \<br/\>Passe': an attack that passes the target without hitting; also a cross-step (see cross). \<br/\>Phrase: a set of related actions and reactions in a conversation. \<br/\>Plaque': a point attack that lands flat. \<br/\>Point: a valid touch; the tip of the sword. \<br/\>Point in Line: also line; an extended arm and blade that threatens the opponent. \<br/\>Pommel: the weight and guard at the extreme end of the blade, opposite the point. \<br/\>Presentation: offering one's blade for engagement by the opponent. \<br/\>Press: an attempt to push the opponent's blade aside or out of line; depending on the opponent's response, the press is followed by a direct or indirect attack. \<br/\>Prime: a parry with the blade down and to the inside, wrist pronated. \<br/\>Principle of Defence: the use of forte against foible when parrying. \<br/\>Prise de Fer: also taking the blade; an engagement of the blades that forces the opponent's weapon into a new line. See: bind, croise, envelopment, opposition. \<br/\>Pronated: when referring to the hand or wrist, facing downwards or backwards; as opposed to supinated. \<br/\>Quarte: a parry with the blade up and to the inside, wrist supinated. \<br/\>Quinte: a parry with the blade up and to the inside, wrist pronated. The blade is held above the head to protect from head cuts. \<br/\>Rapier: a long narrow-bladed thrusting sword, with a complicated guard and little or no edge on the blade. Only recently introduced to the Castle. \<br/\>Redoublement: a new action that follows an attack that missed or was parried; see also reprise."
      </Base:InitialProperty>
      <Base:InitialProperty property="trait:page16">
         "Remise: immediate replacement of an attack that missed or was parried, without withdrawing the arm. \<br/\>Reprise: renewal of an attack that missed or was parried, after a return to en-garde; see also redoublement. \<br/\>Retreat: step back; opposite of advance. \<br/\>Riposte: an attack made immediately after a parry of the opponent's attack. \<br/\>Salle: a hall for the practice of swordplay. \<br/\>Salute: with the weapon, a customary acknowledgement of one's opponent and audience at the start and end of the bout. \<br/\>Second Intention: a false action used to draw a response from the opponent, which will open the opportunity for the intended action that follows, typically a counter-riposte. \<br/\>Seconde: a parry with the blade down and to the outside, wrist pronated. \<br/\>Septime: a parry with the blade down and to the inside, wrist supinated. \<br/\>Simple: an attack or riposte that involves no feints. \<br/\>Single Stick: a form of sword practice with wooden sticks; the sticks themselves. \<br/\>Sixte: a parry with the blade up and to the outside, wrist supinated. \<br/\>Slip: an attack maneuver beginning with a dodge, and culminating in a thrust. \<br/\>Stop Hit: a counter-attack that hits; also a counter-attack whose touch is valid by virtue of its timing. \<br/\>Stop Cut: a stop-hit with the edge. \<br/\>Stop Thrust: a stop-hit with the point. \<br/\>Supinated: when referring to the hand or wrist, facing upwards or forwards; as opposed to pronated. \<br/\>Thrust: an attack made by moving the sword parallel to its length and landing with the point. \<br/\>Tierce: a parry with the blade up and to the outside, wrist pronated. \<br/\>Time: the time required to complete a single, simple action. \<br/\>Time Hit: also time-thrust; old name for stop hit with opposition. \<br/\>Trompement: deception of the parry."
      </Base:InitialProperty>
    </Base:InitialProperties>
    <Core:Properties>
      <Core:Property property="skill:fatigue">1.0</Core:Property>
      <Core:Property property="trait:page00">
         "ART OF THE BLADE\<br/\>\<br/\>"
      </Core:Property>
      <Core:Property property="trait:page01">
         "ART OF THE BLADE\<br/\>\<br/\>By ser Daris\<br/\>\<br/\>I base my system partly on the instruction I received long ago from Lord Bernier, and partly on certain lucid works treating on combat and swordplay. To the authors of those works, to Lord Bernier, and to my many opponents since then, I give thanks for both skill and insight."
      </Core:Property>
      <Core:Property property="trait:page02">
         "THE SWORD\<br/\>\<br/\>The sword consists of two principal parts – the blade and the hilt.\<br/\>\<br/\>The Hilt: The hilt of a sword consists, for simplicity, of everything not part of the blade forward of the guard. A hilt usually consists of a guard, a grip, and a pommel.\<br/\>\<br/\>The Grip: The handle by which the weapon is held, with the strong hand. Usually the grip is made of wood, bone, metal or ivory with leather, wire or cord wrapped around it; it is built around the tang, a continuation of the blade itself. Wood and horn are preferred for the body of the grip, as they absorb some of the shock of combat.\<br/\>\<br/\>The Pommel: At the extreme end of the sword is the pommel. This item, typically a finial, disk or knob of steel, is of sufficient size and weight to balance the sword; the tang is welded, bolted or otherwise securely fasted to it. It also has minor functions: to protect the smaller fingers, to secure the fingers on the grip, and to provide a striking surface for some of the more rowdy bludgeoning blows. \<br/\>\<br/\>The Guard: This portion of the weapon takes many forms, from a brief disc barely larger than the blade itself, to complicated structures or shells surrounding the hand and connecting to the pommel. These structures have their root at the joint between the grip and the blade. The guard is often the most easily discerned difference between various types of swords. The weapon used for military purposes within the castle has a cross-bar blade, also known as a quillon; with sometimes a few smaller curled bars to protect the grip."
      </Core:Property>
      <Core:Property property="trait:page03">
         "The Blade: The blade carries the cutting edge or edges (if any) of the sword and serves to move the point to hit the opponent. The blade as a worked object is divided into three parts: the tang, which fits within the hilt; the forte, the half of the visible blade closest to the guard, and the strongest point of the blade; and the foible, the remaining half of the visible blade at the outer end, and the weakest section. The edges of older swords will be parallel; our more modern weapons taper slightly from the ricasso to the point. Some swords are sharpened completely, partially or not at all on one or both edges; for a practice sword the edges of the blade are neither tapered nor sharpened. Blades may bear one or more fullers (grooves) on each face, or they may have ridges. At the base of the blade, where it meets the hilt, there is usually a short section with an unsharpened – in fact, square – edge: the ricasso. The maker’s mark is usually inscribed or engraved here.\<br/\>\<br/\>The Point: This is of course located at the far end of the blade, on the foible. In a practice or rebated sword the blade is blunted or bent back at the very end, or carries a knob."
      </Core:Property>
      <Core:Property property="trait:page04">
         "Guard [command: guard]\<br/\>\<br/\> A proper guard position is the root of all proper swordplay. Care must be taken not to confuse the term with ‘parry’, a distinct defensive motion for the purpose of stopping a cut or thrust. The guard position defends your strong side from attack and provides the readiest place for a switch to any other defensive position or to an attack. \<br/\>\<br/\>To take the guard position begin with the feet lined up, about shoulder-length apart with front foot pointing towards the opponent and the rear foot perpendicular to the front foot. Bend at the knees, in a half-crouch. The torso should remain straight; you should not lean forward, back or to either side. Bend the weapon arm at the elbow. The distance between the elbow and your body should be one hand length. The traditional “on guard” calls for the blade to be in position for the sixte parry. Your strong arm should be positioned so that your blade will block an attack to your weapon side from hitting your body. Put your weak hand at your hip, or behind your back, or behind the head; unless you are armored, or equipped with, and skilled with, some defensive weapon such as a shield, cloak or dagger. A common flaw of a poor swordsman, experienced or otherwise, is a poorly-learned guard position.\<br/\>\<br/\>Holding the Sword\<br/\>\<br/\>The sword is held lightly but firmly with the thumb along the back of the grip, and the fingers closed round it so that the center knuckles are in line with the edge of the blade. At times the thumb may be shifted to encircle the grip, similarly to the fingers, to relieve the hand."
      </Core:Property>
      <Core:Property property="trait:page05">
         "Defense [command: recover]\<br/\>\<br/\>The parry is a movement of the blade that prevents the opponent's blade from hitting your target.\<br/\>\<br/\> You can be attacked in three basic areas: your guard side, your flank side or your head. Accordingly, there are three main parries used in sword, one for each attack you need to defend against. The guard parry (known as the sixte) has your arm in the guard position with the knuckles facing outward and the blade angled at 45 degrees from your hand. The blade should be in position to block an incoming blow from that angle. When you are in guard this is the parry you should use. The flank parry is made by beginning with a guard parry and bending your hand at the wrist and your arm at the elbow. Your arm should be across your body. Make the head parry by raising your weapon hand bent at the elbow with the blade almost horizontal right above your head about a foot in front of your face. Check all your parries by making sure an attack to that side cannot land. \<br/\>\<br/\>[note that the recover command is automatically part of the attacks, and thus the command is not often employed in actual play; however, training in this important skill will improve a swordsman’s defense ability.]"
      </Core:Property>
      <Core:Property property="trait:page06">
         "The Dodge [command: dodge]\<br/\>\<br/\>Swordsmen in desperate straits may wish to employ any of the variety of dodges and tricks which are known of. Of course, one can only rarely attack while engaged in a dodge; but sometimes this tactic is called for."
      </Core:Property>
      <Core:Property property="trait:page07">
         "The Rest [command: rest]\<br/\>\<br/\>In duels of some duration, or when the opponent is out of reach, the resting guard may prove useful when recovering one’s stamina. Lower the sword hand until the pommel rests on the thigh about six or eight inches above the knee.\<br/\>\<br/\>[note also the command: health]"
      </Core:Property>
      <Core:Property property="trait:page08">
         "Advance \& Retire [commands: advance, retire]\<br/\>\<br/\>If guard is the root of swordplay, the advance and the retire are the main branches of movement. A well executed advance will press your attack against your opponent and force them to react rather then lead, and the best defense against this is a careful retreat. \<br/\>\<br/\>To execute an advance, begin by keeping your body in on guard position. Lift the front foot, toe first, then heel, and put it down one step forward, heel first and then toe. Your upper body should remain still. Next, you should pick up your back foot and place it so that you are again in on guard position. Bring your upper torso forward with your back foot. \<br/\>\<br/\>Retire is essentially like the advance in reverse. Move your feet like in the advance except in the reverse direction and order. Begin by moving your back foot backwards, and then bring back your torso and front foot (toes picked up first, heel put down first. One must conduct a proper retire in order to gain the distance for conducting some maneuvers, such as the lunge.\<br/\>\<br/\>In both the advance and retire, it is important to keep the upper torso perfectly straight. Also make sure that your heels remain lined up and your feet perpendicular. Many beginners have a tendency to let their feet drift out of line, watch this carefully. \<br/\>\<br/\>To practice the advance and retire, go to a place where there is a straight line on the ground, which you can follow. Advance or retreat along that line over and over again. You should get to the point where you don't need to look at the line to keep going straight."
      </Core:Property>
      <Core:Property property="trait:page09">
         "The Thrust [command: thrust, jab]\<br/\>\<br/\> The thrust is the quickest way to get close to your opponent and allows you to move into a defensive position quickly if your attack does not land. For the skilled swordsman, the thrust is the best form of attack, speedy and safe. \<br/\>\<br/\>To thrust, begin in an on guard position. There are two parts to the thrust: the attack and the recovery. The attack delivers the blade to your opponent, and the recovery will bring you back to the guard position. To begin the attack, extend your arm forward pointing towards the center of your opponent's chest. Finish by throwing out your front leg forward so that your knee is at a right angle and when you look down, your leg eclipses your foot. Your back foot should remain firmly planted. Many swordsmen prefer to throw their weak arm out behind them to help channel their momentum into the lunge; this is a matter of preference. \<br/\>\<br/\>The recovery is the simple act of returning to on guard position. Pull back your leg, bringing your torso back, but leave your arm extended. It will make it easier for you to move to a parry (described below). This whole lunge, the attack and the recovery, should be one continuous, swift movement. If there is a pause or a break between movements you will open yourself to attack."
      </Core:Property>
      <Core:Property property="trait:page10">
         "The Slash [command: slash, cut]\<br/\>\<br/\> The slash, an attack performed with the edge of the blade, is not so quickly performed as the thrust; nor is it as safe for the swordsman. However, for a swordsman of superior strength, or a desperate one, this attack may prove useful, as it may can quickly overcome an opponent. \<br/\>\<br/\>To slash, begin in an on guard position. Slashes may be made vertically, horizontally upwards or downwards, or horizontally. The common slash, downward horizontally from your strong side, is made as follows: extend the sword arm somewhat, the hand to be in quarte, and the point a little raised, the hilt of the sword being about the height of the chin, and the edge directed obliquely downwards towards your weak side. Then, drop the point diagonally downwards from your strong side to your weak side, taking care that the edge leads during the passage of the blade along the line on the target; then allow the wrist to revolve so as to bring the thumb downwards, and the back of the hand and the flat of the blade opposite your weak side, and cause the sword to describe a complete circle, thus bringing it again to the position of guard. These movements are carried out continuously, and when done well is a useful tool of the swordsman."
      </Core:Property>
      <Core:Property property="trait:page11">
         "Advanced Attacks: The Feint [command: feint]\<br/\>\<br/\> Many times a thrust or lunge attack will not be enough to strike your opponent. They only have to move their blade a short distance to execute a parry while the point of your sword needs to travel a much greater distance before that parry can be made. Because of this compound attacks were created. These are attacks of at least two parts that make it harder for your opponent to parry. The most common compound attack is the feint attack. To perform a feint, extend your point towards one side of your opponent, and then switch your line to the other side in the middle of the lunge. If your feint was convincing, then your opponent will try to parry it as if it were an attack. When you attack to their other side, they will have to work harder to parry it. You can feint many times with one action. You perform an attack, starting with your blade towards one line on the advance, then another at the beginning of the thrust and finishing with a different line. If you can do it well, the opponent will have no idea where to parry."
      </Core:Property>
      <Core:Property property="trait:page12">
         "Advanced Attacks: The Lunge [command: lunge]\<br/\>\<br/\>The lunge is a combination move beginning with an advance and ending with a thrust as the attack; two of the most basic moves in swordplay. But the advance lunge itself is so much more than basic; it is a distance gaining move and powerful attack, and a strategy to get the advantage of an opponent. It can lend great power to quick movement. Many complex bladework moves can be executed during the advancing lunge such as the pris de fer (taking of the iron), a move that shows total control of the situation and beautiful finesse of movement. In short, the advance lunge can stand for everything that is beautiful about the art of the sword. \<br/\>\<br/\>To conduct a lunge, one must first gain the proper distance from one’s opponent; the opponent might first retreat, or the swordsman may retire to the correct measure."
      </Core:Property>
      <Core:Property property="trait:page13">
         "Advanced Attacks: The Slip [command: slip]\<br/\>\<br/\>The slip is a very sophisticated combination attack, in which the swordsman dodges aside, defending against the opponent's blade, and makes a thrust. The slip is somewhat slow to recover from -- a period of great danger. Few novices at swordplay can succeed in a slip; but for the skilled, it is a powerful tool."
      </Core:Property>
      <Core:Property property="trait:page14">
         "Advance: a movement forward by step, cross, or balestra. \<br/\>Attack: the initial offensive action made by extending the sword arm and continuously threatening the opponent. \<br/\>Attack au Fer: an attack that is prepared by deflecting the opponent's blade, e.g. beat, froissement, pressure. \<br/\>Balestra: a forward hop or jump, typically followed by an attack such as a lunge or fleche. \<br/\>Beat: an attempt to knock the opponent's blade aside or out of line by using one's foible against the opponent's foible. \<br/\>Bind: an action in which the opponent's blade is forced into the diagonally opposite line. \<br/\>Bout: swordplay practice at which the score is kept; or, a single conversation without a wound being inflicted. \<br/\>Broadsword: an older military sword; any straight-bladed, double-edged, single-handed cutting sword. \<br/\>Broken Time: a sudden change in the tempo of one swordsman's actions, used to fool the opponent into responding at the wrong time. \<br/\>Button: the blunted tip on the end of some practice swords. \<br/\>Change of Engagement: engagement of the opponent's blade in the opposite line. \<br/\>Compound: also composed; an attack or riposte incorporating one or more feints to the opposite line that the action finishes in. \<br/\>Conversation: the back-and-forth play of the blades in a bout, composed of phrases punctuated by gaps of no blade action. \<br/\>Counter-attack: an attack made against the right-of-way, or in response to the opponent's attack. \<br/\>Counter-disengage: a disengage in the opposite direction, to deceive the counter-parry. \<br/\>Counter-parry: a parry made in the opposite line to the attack; i.e. the defender first comes around to the opposite side of the opponent's blade. \<br/\>Counter-riposte: an attack that follows a parry of the opponent's riposte. \<br/\>Counter-time: an attack that responds to the opponent's counter-attack, typically a riposte following the parry of the counter-attack. \<br/\>Coupe': also cut-over; an attack or deception that passes around the opponent's tip. \<br/\>Croise: also semi-bind; an action in which the opponent's blade is forced into the high or low line on the same side. \<br/\>Cross: an advance or retreat by crossing one leg over the other; also either a forward cross or backwards cross. \<br/\>Cut: an attack made with a chopping motion of the blade, landing with the edge or point. \<br/\>Deception: avoidance of an attempt to engage the blades; see disengage, coupe' \<br/\>Derobement: deception of the attack au fer or prise de fer. \<br/\>Direct: an attack or riposte that finishes in the same line in which it was formed, with no feints out of that line. \<br/\>Disengage: a circular movement of the blade that deceives the opponent's parry, removes the blades from engagement, or changes the line of engagement. \<br/\>Displacement: moving the target to avoid an attack; dodging. \<br/\>Double': an attack or riposte that describes a complete circle around the opponent's blade, and finishes in the opposite line. \<br/\>Dry: a bout with practice weapons, as opposed to wet, a bout or duel of where there is risk of blood. \<br/\>Engagement: when the blades are in contact with each other, e.g. during a parry, attack au fer, prise de fer, or graze. \<br/\>En Garde: also on guard; the basic position; the stance that swordsmen assume when preparing to engage; the guard position subsequent to the salute. \<br/\>Envelopment: an engagement that sweeps the opponent's blade through a full circle. \<br/\>False: an action that is intended to fail, but draw a predicted reaction from the opponent; also, the back edge of a blade with only one sharp edge. \<br/\>Feint: attacking into one line with the intention of switching to another line before the attack is completed. \<br/\>Finta in tempo: lit. \\"feint in time\\"; a feint of counter-attack that draws a counter-time parry, which is deceived. \<br/\>Fleche: lit. \\"arrow\\"; an attack in which the aggressor leaps off his leading foot, attempts to make the hit, and then passes the opponent at a run."
      </Core:Property>
      <Core:Property property="trait:page15">
         "Flying Parry or Riposte: a parry with a backwards glide and riposte by cut-over. \<br/\>Foible: the upper, weaker part of the blade. \<br/\>Forte: the lower, strong part of the blade. \<br/\>Froissement: an attack that displaces the opponent's blade by a strong grazing action. \<br/\>Graze: also glissade; an attack or feint that slides along the opponent's blade. \<br/\>Guard: the metal cup, ba, bars or bow that protects the hand from being hit. Also, the defensive position assumed when not attacking. \<br/\>Hilt: the handle of a sword, consisting of guard, grip, and pommel. \<br/\>In Quartata: an attack made with a quarter turn to the inside, concealing the front but exposing the back. \<br/\>In Time: when a stop-hit arrives at least one ‘time’ before the original attack. \<br/\>Indirect: an attack or riposte that finishes in the opposite line to which it was formed, by means of a disengage or coupe'. \<br/\>Insistence: forcing an attack through the parry. \<br/\>Interception: a counter-attack that intercepts and checks an indirect attack or other disengagement. \<br/\>Invitation: a line that is intentionally left open to encourage the opponent to attack. \<br/\>Line: the main direction of an attack (e.g., high/low, inside/outside), often equated to the parry that must be made to deflect the attack; also point in line. \<br/\>Longsword: the ordinary military and duelling weapon of the castle, with a tapering double-edged blade useable for both cut and thrust work; normally having a simple crossbar guard. \<br/\>Lunge: a thrusting attack made by extending the rear leg and landing on the bent front leg. \<br/\>Mal-parry: a parry that fails to prevent the attack from landing. \<br/\>Measure: the distance between opponents. \<br/\>Neuvieme: an unconventional parry sometimes described as ‘blade behind the back’, pointing down (a variant of octave), other times similar to elevated sixte. \<br/\>Octave: parry with the blade down and to the outside, wrist supinated. \<br/\>Opposition: holding the opponent's blade in a non-threatening line; a time-hit; any attack or counter-attack with opposition. \<br/\>Parry: a block of the attack, made with the forte of one's own blade. \<br/\>Pass: an attack made with a cross; e.g. fleche. Also, the act of moving past the opponent. \<br/\>Passata-sotto: a lunge made by dropping one hand to the floor. \<br/\>Passe': an attack that passes the target without hitting; also a cross-step (see cross). \<br/\>Phrase: a set of related actions and reactions in a conversation. \<br/\>Plaque': a point attack that lands flat. \<br/\>Point: a valid touch; the tip of the sword. \<br/\>Point in Line: also line; an extended arm and blade that threatens the opponent. \<br/\>Pommel: the weight and guard at the extreme end of the blade, opposite the point. \<br/\>Presentation: offering one's blade for engagement by the opponent. \<br/\>Press: an attempt to push the opponent's blade aside or out of line; depending on the opponent's response, the press is followed by a direct or indirect attack. \<br/\>Prime: a parry with the blade down and to the inside, wrist pronated. \<br/\>Principle of Defence: the use of forte against foible when parrying. \<br/\>Prise de Fer: also taking the blade; an engagement of the blades that forces the opponent's weapon into a new line. See: bind, croise, envelopment, opposition. \<br/\>Pronated: when referring to the hand or wrist, facing downwards or backwards; as opposed to supinated. \<br/\>Quarte: a parry with the blade up and to the inside, wrist supinated. \<br/\>Quinte: a parry with the blade up and to the inside, wrist pronated. The blade is held above the head to protect from head cuts. \<br/\>Rapier: a long narrow-bladed thrusting sword, with a complicated guard and little or no edge on the blade. Only recently introduced to the Castle. \<br/\>Redoublement: a new action that follows an attack that missed or was parried; see also reprise."
      </Core:Property>
      <Core:Property property="trait:page16">
         "Remise: immediate replacement of an attack that missed or was parried, without withdrawing the arm. \<br/\>Reprise: renewal of an attack that missed or was parried, after a return to en-garde; see also redoublement. \<br/\>Retreat: step back; opposite of advance. \<br/\>Riposte: an attack made immediately after a parry of the opponent's attack. \<br/\>Salle: a hall for the practice of swordplay. \<br/\>Salute: with the weapon, a customary acknowledgement of one's opponent and audience at the start and end of the bout. \<br/\>Second Intention: a false action used to draw a response from the opponent, which will open the opportunity for the intended action that follows, typically a counter-riposte. \<br/\>Seconde: a parry with the blade down and to the outside, wrist pronated. \<br/\>Septime: a parry with the blade down and to the inside, wrist supinated. \<br/\>Simple: an attack or riposte that involves no feints. \<br/\>Single Stick: a form of sword practice with wooden sticks; the sticks themselves. \<br/\>Sixte: a parry with the blade up and to the outside, wrist supinated. \<br/\>Slip: an attack maneuver beginning with a dodge, and culminating in a thrust. \<br/\>Stop Hit: a counter-attack that hits; also a counter-attack whose touch is valid by virtue of its timing. \<br/\>Stop Cut: a stop-hit with the edge. \<br/\>Stop Thrust: a stop-hit with the point. \<br/\>Supinated: when referring to the hand or wrist, facing upwards or forwards; as opposed to pronated. \<br/\>Thrust: an attack made by moving the sword parallel to its length and landing with the point. \<br/\>Tierce: a parry with the blade up and to the outside, wrist pronated. \<br/\>Time: the time required to complete a single, simple action. \<br/\>Time Hit: also time-thrust; old name for stop hit with opposition. \<br/\>Trompement: deception of the parry."
      </Core:Property>
      <Core:Property property="volition">0</Core:Property>
    </Core:Properties>
    <Notes:Notes>
      <Notes:Category cat="QA" catstate="Open">
        <Notes:Note ix="971734080" state="Comment" user="michaelb">
           Daris's manual on fencing.
        </Notes:Note>
      </Notes:Category>
    </Notes:Notes>
  </Base:Thing>
</object>
