<object clone="/obj/properties" owner="zwoc">
  <Core:PropertyContainer>
    <Ur:UrObject/>
    <Core:PCProperties>
      <Core:Property property="howto_setup_a_cnpc">
         X[M] /*

HOW TO SETUP A CNPC

FIRSTLY: Be aware that this system is still in its infant
stage. Do not expect things to work as they should, but feel
free to notify me [kalle@marrach.skotos.net] about potential
issues you may encounter.

1-2-3 HOW TO CREATE A CNPC:

1.) Create a regular object body for your CNPC. A cat, dog,
mouse, etc. Or use yourself. BUT BE AWARE: If you're using
yourself that there will be a huge amount of debug
information during e.g. library modifications.

Once you're done creating or deciding what object you'll be
using,

2.) Prepare the body to use the NIP system by typing:
\> +nip "set Woe:name:of:object"

This will in most cases result in:

WELCOME TO THE 'NIP' CNPC SYSTEM!

Hold one moment while the core library is set up in \<Woe:name:of:object\> ...
--\> Implementing base.
--\> Adding base libraries.
--\> Inserting system signals.
Done!

(If you chose to put the system in yourself, you will have a
LOT more info than that.)

And now you're DONE. To add/remove libraries etc. to the
system, peek at the block below.

To start the CNPC, you need to (currently) do:
\> +tool merry exec Call( \$\{Woe:for:your:NPC\}, "heartbeat" );

To stop it again, do:
\> +nip npc "sig term"

Note that the NPC must be in the room for you to be able to do the +nip call.

*/
      </Core:Property>
      <Core:Property property="modifying_your_cnpc">
         X[M] /*

MODIFYING YOUR CNPC

1.) Where can I figure out what I can add to the CNPC?
--) You can currently only figure that out by opening up woe
    and scanning through Lib:NIP:lib, Lib:NIP:hooks, and
    Lib:NIP:signals.
    The Lib:NIP:base-folder contains preloaded core stuff.
    that you needn't worry about in most cases (they're
    always loaded).
    For a complete list of possible locations, check out
    Data:NIP:system/lib_path

2.) So, I found a library I want to add. How do I do it?
--) There are a few options:
  A.) Through WOE:
    I.) Open the CNPC object,
    II.) Open up the Core Properties,
    III.) [E]dit a random property or add a new property and
          edit that,
    IV.) Change the PROPERTY NAME to add
    V.) Change the PROPERTY VALUE to the name of the
        library.
    VI.) Click SUBMIT and your library should be loaded.

  B.) Through the client, using +setp:
    I.) Simply type: +setp "Woe:name:of:object add lib-name"
      e.g.:
      \> +setp "Marrach:Coders:kalle:Charles add sleeping"

3.) Okay, that was fun. How do I remove the library again?
--) Do as mentioned previously, but replace add with delete.

4.) There are a lot of properties in my CNPC. Any
    categorizing there, or ...?
--) Indeed:

nip-core:* These properties are core props and are usually
           and frequently modified by the system itself, and
           should in 99% of the cases be left untouched.
nip:*      These properties are a bit more close-to-earth.
           They should each be scanned through and you
           should hopefully know what each and every one
           does for your CNPC.
           Examples are parameters for the sleeping rhythm,
           a.s.o.
npc:*      The properties beginning with 'npc:' are mostly
           used to declare the CURRENT state of the CNPC.
           Such as weariness, hunger, thirst, etc. They may
           be modified, but it's not a must.

*/
      </Core:Property>
      <Core:Property property="revisions">
         (\{ 1050953846, "zwoc", "E" \})
      </Core:Property>
    </Core:PCProperties>
    <Notes:Notes/>
  </Core:PropertyContainer>
</object>
