<object clone="/obj/properties" owner="TextIF">
  <Core:PropertyContainer>
    <Ur:UrObject/>
    <Core:PCProperties>
      <Core:Property property="author">
         "Written by Kalle Alm \<kalle@mortalis.skotos.net\>"
      </Core:Property>
      <Core:Property property="command">"+man"</Core:Property>
      <Core:Property property="description">
         "+man is the system's manual pager. It is used to look up information on specific commands.\\r\\n\\r\\nManual pages are either local or global. Global manual pages, available on every server, can only be written from the master server (at point of writing, Castle Marrach server); local pages, only available on the server where they were written, can be added/modified anywhere. Local manual pages take precedence over global.\\r\\n\\r\\nA manual page consists of several parts.\\r\\n\\r\\nThey may be labelled NAME, SYNOPSIS, DESCRIPTION, EXAMPLES, OPTIONS, AUTHOR, and SEE ALSO.\\r\\n\\r\\nThe following conventions apply to the SYNOPSIS section and can be used as a guide in other sections.\\r\\n\\r\\n\<text\>           required argument\\r\\n[\<text\>]         optional argument\\r\\n[a\|b\|c]          optional flags\\r\\na\|b\|c            only one of a, b or c is required\\r\\n\<text\> ...       argument is repeatable\\r\\n[expression] ... entire expression within [ ] is repeatable\\r\\n\\r\\nThe command or function illustration is a pattern that should match all possible invocations. In some cases it is advisable to illustrate several exclusive invocations."
      </Core:Property>
      <Core:Property property="examples">
         "+man info\\r\\n     Display the manual page for the command +info\\r\\n\\r\\n+man write info\\r\\n     Open up the page editor for the manual entry for +info\\r\\n\\r\\n+man write local info\\r\\n     Open up the page editor for the local manual entry for +info\\r\\n\\r\\n+man delete info\\r\\n     Delete the manual entry for +info\\r\\n\\r\\n+man content\\r\\n     List all commands available in the +man database currently, global and local."
      </Core:Property>
      <Core:Property property="last_mod">1095350067</Core:Property>
      <Core:Property property="options">
         "write \<command\>\\r\\n     Write a new, or edit an old, entry in the manual database for \<command\>.\\r\\n\\r\\ndelete \<command\>\\r\\n     Erase the manual entry for \<command\>.\\r\\n"
      </Core:Property>
      <Core:Property property="revisions">
         (\{ 1135371987, "-", "SYNC" \})
      </Core:Property>
      <Core:Property property="synopsis">
         "+man [write\|delete] \<command\>\\r\\n+man content"
      </Core:Property>
    </Core:PCProperties>
    <Notes:Notes/>
  </Core:PropertyContainer>
</object>
