<object clone="/obj/properties" owner="TextIF">
  <Core:PropertyContainer>
    <Ur:UrObject/>
    <Core:PCProperties>
      <Core:Property property="command">"+page"</Core:Property>
      <Core:Property property="description">
         "The paging system is used to send text messages to others online, by account name (+page) or by character body name.\\r\\nIt holds a recall in memory which can be accessed using the recall option. It can be used to send messages to people on the same server, but also people on distant servers, e.g. Skotos Seven.\\r\\nThe +page command (staff version) varies slightly from the @page command. A number of differences are:\\r\\n- It ignores page consent. A person could have busy on, or have you on page block, and your page would go through regardless.\\r\\n- It bypasses page accept. A person targeted with a +page will not be prompted to accept your page. The page will appear immediately, regardless of accept list.\\r\\n- It cannot take the 'recall' flag. Use @page.\\r\\n- It allows you to target account names rather than just character bodies.\\r\\nThis manual page does not cover the non-staff version further than explaining the differences."
      </Core:Property>
      <Core:Property property="examples">
         "+page zwoc \\"Hey, Zwoc.\\"\\r\\n      Send a message to the account Zwoc. The page will end up in whichever one of Zwoc's logged in bodies that is least idle. (Paging by account name can only be done to people on the same server.)\\r\\n+page kalle \\"Hey, Kalle.\\"\\r\\n      Send a message to the character body Kalle.\\r\\n+page geli@lovecraft \\"Hey, Geli.\\"\\r\\n      Send a message to Geli on the server identified as \\"Lovecraft\\"."
      </Core:Property>
      <Core:Property property="last_mod">1095564551</Core:Property>
      <Core:Property property="revisions">
         (\{ 1135372000, "-", "SYNC" \})
      </Core:Property>
      <Core:Property property="see_also">"+opage"</Core:Property>
      <Core:Property property="synopsis">
         "+page \<account\>\|\<name\>[@\<server\>] \\"\<message\>\\""
      </Core:Property>
    </Core:PCProperties>
    <Notes:Notes/>
  </Core:PropertyContainer>
</object>
